Okay, alright, let's lots of discuss today,
好的，今天有很多东西要讨论，
so I'm gonna [plow right] through everything.
所以我要把所有东西[]。
So again, a quick reminder,
再次提醒一下，
upcoming events now correct dates,
即将到来的活动现在改正了日期，
so today, at 4:30 over Zoom,
所以今天，在 4:30 通过 Zoom ，
we're going to have the Co founder of Postgres ML,
我们将有 Postgres ML 的联合创始人，
basically a modified version of Postgres
基本上是 Postgres 的修改版本，
or it's not Postgres isn't modified,
或它不是 Postgres 修改的，
they're building off the extension system and API in Postgres,
他们建立 Postgres 的扩展系统和 API ，
to support machine learning frameworks and large language models directly inside of Postgres,
来直接在 Postgres 内部支持机器学习框架和大型语言模型，
he's going to talk about the stuff that they've been building,
他将在谈论他们在构建的东西，
next week, we have probably one of the bigger vector database companies come to give a talk Weaviate,
下周，我们可能有一家更大的矢量数据库公司来做演讲， Weaviate ，
and then after that, it's going to be FeatureForm
然后在它之后将是 FeatureForm ，
and after FeatureForm its FeatureBase, right,
在 FeatureForm 之后是 FeatureBase ，
same name, different systems.
相同的名字，不同的系统。
Again, this is optional by all means attend if you want.
再说一次，这是可选的，如果你想参加的话。
And then as I post on Piazza,
然后，我在 Piazza 贴上，
while sending out an email to the database friends,
给数据库的朋友们发了一封电子邮件，
companies like theses,
像这样的公司，
with everyone's CVs,
附着大家的简历，
if you, if you uploaded it yesterday.
如果你昨天上传了。
All right.
好的。
So last class we talked about hash tables
上一节课，我们讨论了哈希表，
and we talked how this important data structure,
我们讨论了这个重要的数据结构，
that's going to give us this nice O(1) average time complexity
它会给我们带来很好的 O(1) 平均时间复杂度，
to do lookup matching keys to values.
来查找键和值的匹配。
And we spent time talking about how there was this differentiation between static and dynamic hashing schemes,
我们花时间讨论了静态和动态哈希方法之间的区别，
like static was used of fixed size number of slots,
比如静态使用的是固定大小 slot 数量，
whereas the extendible hashing, chain hashing and linear hashing
而可扩展哈希、链式哈希和线性哈希，
all had the ability to grow incrementally over time
都具有随时间递增增长的能力，
to accommodate more more keys than you originally envisioned.
以容纳比你最初设想的更多的键。
So the main takeaway from last class should be,
所以，上一节课的主要收获应该是，
we spent most of our time talking about how to deal with the complex,
我们花了大部分时间讨论如何处理这个复杂的问题，
two keys, hash two different keys hash to the same location, what do you do,
两个键，两个不同的键哈希到相同的位置，你会做什么，
and then we mostly talk about,
然后我们主要讨论了，
how these hash tables are primarily going to be used in most systems for internal data structures,
这些哈希表将如何在大多数系统中主要用于内部数据结构，
like your page table and project 1, or the page directory
比如如页表和项目 1 ，或页面目录，
or the other thing is keeping track of what's the state of of the database system itself,
或跟踪数据库系统本身的状态的其他东西，
while we're running,
当我们运行时，
we'll see hash tables again,
我们将再次看到哈希表，
when we talk about how to you Joins sufficiently,
当我们谈论如何 Join 时，
but again for the most part
但是，在大多数情况下，
these are primarily used for internal data structures.
它们主要用于内部数据结构。
So today's class we're now talking about B+ trees
所以今天的课程，我们现在讨论的是 B+ 树，
and these are going to be primarily the default choice,
它们将主要是默认的选择，
when you want to have an index in, in a relational database system.
当你想要在关系数据库系统中建立索引时。
So if you call CREATE INDEX,
所以如果你调用 CREATE INDEX ，
yeah 99% of the time, in most systems,
是的， 99% 的情况下，在大多数系统中，
you'll be getting something that looks like A B plus tree,
你会得到一个看起来像 B+ 树的东西。
Then we'll talk about,
然后我们再讨论一下，
so we'll first go a high level overview
我们将首先进行一个高层次的概述，
of what a B plus tree looks like,
B+ 树是什么样子的，
what makes it,
它是什么组成的，
what's the plus, and B+ tree versus regular B tree.
B+ 树与常规的 B 树相比。
And I'll talk about some basic design choices,
我将讨论一些基本的设计选择，
how when we actually want to build one
当我们想要构建一个系统时，
and then we'll finish up
我们将结束，
to to the time we have,
直到我们有时间，
to that we have time at the end,
直到我们有的最后的时间，
talk about all the different ways
讨论所有不同的方法，
you can actually optimize and improve performance of these different systems
你可以实际优化和提高这些不同系统的性能，
and the examples real systems are actually doing today.
以及真实系统今天在做的例子。
Okay?
好的？
All right, so the first we got to discuss is what is a B+ tree.
好的，所以我们首先要讨论的是什么是 B+ 树。
And so the B+ tree is in a category of data structures called B trees,
B+ 树属于一种称为 B 树的数据结构，
and what's sort of confusing about this in database literature,
在数据库文献中，令人困惑的是，
different database systems, is that,
不同的数据库系统中，
there's the class of the data structure called B trees,
有一类数据结构被称为 B 树，
and then there's a specific data structure called B tree,
然后是一种特殊的数据结构，称为 B 树，
and then some database systems are actually using B+ trees,
然后一些数据库系统实际上使用的是 B+ 树，
but they're going to call themselves a B tree, right.
但他们将自己称为 B 树。
So if you go look at the Postgres code,
所以如果你去看 Postgres 代码，
they're going to refer to their data structure as a B tree,
他们会把他们的数据结构称为 B 树，
but as far as I can tell, it's a B+ tree,
但据我所知，这是一棵 B+ 树，
with some modern techniques, like from the B-Link tree, right.
使用了一些现代技术，比如 B-Link 树。
So it's sort of, when B, when you say B+ tree,
所以当你说 B+ 树的时候，
it's typically going to mean a bunch of these other different things.
它通常指的是其他一些不同的东西。
So, there is no original paper on the B+ tree,
所以， B+ 树没有原始论文，
actually, the one that everyone cites is this one from 1979,
大家提到的这个是 1979 年的这个，
by the guys at IBM talking about the,
由 IBM 的人谈论，
what they call it, the ubiquitous B tree,
他们称为无处不在的 B 树，
and in then this they describe,
然后他们描述说，
hey, there's this, the different variants,
嘿，有这个不同的变种，
but the most common one that's gonna be most useful for database systems is gonna be a B+ tree,
但对数据库系统最有用的是 B+ 树，
And then they cite some kind of IBM tech report,
然后他们引用了某种 IBM 技术报告，
that I have not been able to find,
我没有找到，
I didn't look that hard,
我没有那么认真地找，
but it doesn't show up right on Google,
但它在 Google 上没有显示出来，
that that's the one where they talk about the, the original B+ tree.
这是他们谈论的那个原始 B+ 树，
The original authors of what the of of the B+ work,
关于 B+ 的原始作者，
this guy bear and the credit,
这个人承担的责任和功劳，
they never actually define what the B means in B+ tree,
他们从未真正定义过 B+ 树中 B 的意思，
typically people say it's, it's for balanced, broad, bushy,
通常人们说它是，代表平衡，宽广，浓密，
the guy's name is Bayer, b a y e r,
这个人的名字是 Bayer ， b a y er ，
so could have nameded after himself,
所以可能是以他自己的名字命名的，
this data structure actually developed at Boeing, like the airplane companies,
这个数据结构实际上是 Boeing 开发的，那个飞机公司，
could have been Boeing tree,
可能是 Boeing 树，
nobody really knows,
没有人真正知道，
but typically people,
但通常情况下，
when you say B tree, people typically mean balanced.
当你说 B 树时，人们通常指的是平衡。
There's another variant called B-Link tree,
还有另一个变体叫做 B-Link 树，
and as I said, there'll be the sort of classic B+ tree,
正如我所说的，有一种经典的 B+ 树，
but nobody implements exactly as it's defined there,
但没有人实现它的定义，
people gonna borrow bits and pieces of it
人们会零星地借用它，
and in particular what they're gonna borrow some ideas from this B-Link tree paper,
特别是他们会从这篇 B-Link 树论文中借用一些想法，
that actually came from here at CMU in in 1981,
这篇论文实际上来自 CMU ，在 1981 年，
certain guy by Philip Lehman,
这个人是 Philip Lehman ，
that dude still works in the dean's office at CMU on the 5th floor,
那个家伙仍在 CMU 五楼的院长办公室工作，
and if you go look at the Postgres source code,
如果你去看 Postgres 源代码，
in the the directory where they talk about of B tree,
在他们谈论 B 树的目录中，
notice they say B tree instead of B+ tree
注意他们说的是 B 树而不是 B+ 树，
and there is an nbtree,
这里有一个 nbtree ，
because it's a non balance B+ tree,
因为这是一个非平衡 B+ 树，
but we'll get to that later.
但我们稍后会谈到这个。
But yeah, right here in the source,
但是，是的，就在这个代码中，
oh yeah, this is a correct implication,
是的，这是一个正确的暗示，
correct is always important,
正确总是重要的，
of Lehman and Yao's paper from the B-Link tree, from 1973, right,
关于 Lehman 和 Yao 的 B-Link 论文，在 1973 年，
that's kind of cool.
这太酷了。
But again we're going to focus primarily on this one,
但我们将主要关注这个，
we'll see if we have time,
我们将看看是否有时间，
I'll talk about the Bε tree at the end,
我将在最后讨论 Bε 树，
and then the Bw tree is a thing of Microsoft,
然后， Bw 树是微软的东西，
a lock-free version of B+ tree.
一种 B+ 树的无锁版本。
We actually implemented that here CMU
我们实际上在 CMU 实现了这个，
and was not easy
这并不容易，
and we have an open source implementation of that.
我们有一个开放源码的实现。
Okay.
好的。
So the B+ tree is going to be a self balanced order tree,
所以 B+ 树是一个自平衡的排序树，
that's going to allow us to do searches and sequential access and insertions and deletions,
它允许我们进行搜索和顺序访问，以及插入和删除，
all in log n time, right,
所有这些都在 log n 时间内，
log n is going to be the height of the tree.
log n 是树的高度。
And so the, the difference between,
所以，这里的区别，
what we'll describe here and B+ tree versus a generic binary search tree is that,
我们在这里描述的 B+ 树和一般的二叉搜索树之间的区别是，
the nodes in our data structure can have obviously more than two, two keys,
我们数据结构中的节点显然可以有两个以上的键，
and the reason why we're going to want this is because,
我们想要这个的原因是，
again, we want to convert,
我们想要转换，
we want to minimize amount of random I/O we're doing,
我们想要最小化我们做的随机 I/O 量，
so we want to maximize amount of sequential I/O,
我们想要最大化顺序 I/O 量，
and the B+ tree is going to be perfect for us to do this,
B+ 树是非常适合我们这样做的，
because when we land in a node, that's essentially fetching in a page
因为当我们到达一个在获取页面的节点时，
and we don't have, we don't have as many keys as we can inside that,
我们没有尽可能多的键在里面，
before we have to move on, to grab the next piece of next page from disk, right.
在我们继续，从磁盘中获取下一个页面之前。
So thinking back, way back in the 1970s,
所以回想一下，早在 20 世纪 70 年代，
when hardware was terrible,
当硬件很糟糕的时候，
like you had a minimum amount of RAM,
比如你有最少的 RAM ，
but your disk was also super slow,
你的磁盘也超级慢，
so a B+ tree,
所以 B+ 树，
it's going to allow you to convert,
它将允许转换，
when you do these lookup,
当你做这些查找时，
from random I/O into sequential access.
从随机 I/O 转换为顺序访问。
Because once you follow the leaf nodes
因为一旦你跟随叶节点，
or follow the the the tree down to the leaf nodes,
或沿着树向下到叶节点，
and once you're down there,
一旦你到了那里，
you never go back up,
你再也不会回到上面，
not entirely true,
不完全正确，
but for our purposes,
但出于我们的目的，
now we'll assume that's the case,
我们现在假设情况就是这样，
and then I can scan along the leaf nodes
然后我可以沿着叶节点扫描，
to find the data I'm looking for, right.
以找到我正在寻找的数据。
So more formative, we can say,
所以，更具形式性的，我们可以说，
that a B+ tree is going to be M-way search tree with the following properties,
B+ 树是具有以下性质的 M 路搜索树，
for us, is that it be perfectly balanced,
对我们来说，它是完全平衡的，
meaning that the every leaf node in our tree structure is going to have the same depth,
这意味着我们树结构中的每个叶节点都将具有相同的深度，
means, the same number of levels down from the root to that that leaf node,
也就是从根到该叶节点的相同层数，
and again, Postgres is going to violate this little bit,
再次， Postgres 会违反这一点，
some, some people do,
有些人是这样做的，
but the very beginning assume that's the case.
但是从一开始就认为情况是这样。
We also have a rule,
我们还有一条规则，
that every node other than the root has to be at least half-full,
除根节点之外的每个节点都必须至少半满，
so if I, if I can have M keys in my, in my, in my, in my node,
所以如果我有 M 个键在一个节点中，
I need to have at least half a number of nodes,
我需要至少有一半的节点，
half a number of keys as possible, up to the maximum number, right,
尽可能有最大数量一半的键，
if I go below that threshold,
如果我低于这个阈值，
if I go below mean less than half-full,
如果我低于半满，
then I have to do some merging,
那么我必须进行一些合并，
but again, we can, we can, we can tweak that requirement later on.
但是再次，我们可以稍后对这个要求进行调整。
And so then the root would be special case,
根节点是特殊的，
so we can ignore it for now,
所以我们现在可以忽略它，
and then every inner node with k keys are going to have at least k+1 non-null children,
然后每个有 k 个键的内部节点将至少有 k+1 个非空子节点，
meaning I could have some locations,
这意味着我可以有一些位置，
or pointer, possible pointers to leaf nodes or nodes below me,
或者指向我下面的叶节点或节点的可能指针，
when I'm inner node,
当我是内部节点时，
but I don't have to have the max number.
但我不一定要有最大数量。
So this is all math,
所以这都是数学问题，
let's look at example.
让我们来看一个例子。
So here's a really simple,
所以这里有一个非常简单的，
here's a really simple 2-way B+ tree,
这里有一个非常简单的 2 阶 B+ 树，
and we can define the root node at the top
我们可以定义顶部的根节点，
and then the inner nodes,
然后是内部节点，
because we only have three levels,
因为我们只有三层，
the inner nodes are just the ones in the middle,
内部节点就是中间的那些，
and then the leaf nodes are the things at the bottom.
然后叶节点就是底部的东西。
So with inner node itself,
所以，在内部节点本身中，
we're going to have this alternating pattern
我们将有这种交替模式，
between a pointer to another node and then a key,
一个指向另一个节点的指针和一个键，
and then in the leaf nodes,
然后在叶节点中，
there'll be the value that we're trying to store for this for a given key,
将有我们试图为给定键存储的值，
and for now, we're not going to find what the value is,
目前，我们不会找到值是什么，
but you can think of it like potentially the record ID
但你可以将其视为潜在的记录 ID ，
to point to the actual tuple, some page number, page number and offset,
以指向实际的 tuple ，某个页码和偏移量，
or if it's a case of MySQL or SQLite,
或者，如果这是 MySQL 或 SQLite 的情况，
it could actually be the tuple itself,
它可能是 tuple 本身，
but for now, we can ignore that.
但就目前而言，我们可以忽略这个。
And so the way to think about these numbers here in the inner nodes and the root nodes,
所以思考这些内部节点和根节点中的数字的方法是，
that these are essentially guideposts,
这些基本上是路标，
that tell you which path you want to go down, right.
告诉你要走哪条路径。
So at the root node here,
所以在这里的根节点，
we only have one key, it's 20,
我们只有一个键，它是 20 ，
so if you're going to go left to it,
所以如果你去左边，
it's any value, any key value that's going to be less than 20,
它是任何小于 20 的值，
and we'll go right, greater than or equal to, right.
我们去右边，就会得到大于或等于的。
Same thing, the next one, I have 10 here,
一样的东西，下一个，我这里有 10 ，
less than 10 goes here,
小于 10 的到这边，
greater than equal to 10 goes on the other side.
大于等于 10 的在另一边。
So what makes?
那么什么造成？
So this is sort of what I'm describing so far,
这就是我到目前为止所描述的，
this is a basic B+ tree,
这是一个基本的 B+ 树，
but what I was saying before that they have this,
但我之前说过，他们有这个，
we're borrowing ideas from other papers like the B-Link tree,
我们借鉴了其他论文的想法，比如 B-Link 树，
is that the nodes are also going to have sibling pointers at every level,
也就是节点也将在每个级别上有兄弟指针，
so I think the textbook might only show at the leaf nodes,
我认为课本可能只在叶节点上显示，
Postgres puts them in the middle node, the inner nodes as well,
Postgres 将它们放在中间节点，也是内部节点，
and I think the original B-Link paper had the nodes as well.
我认为原始的 B-Link 论文也有这些节点。
And so the reason why this matters is,
所以这很重要的原因是，
again, if I'm doing search,
如果我要进行搜索，
give me all the keys greater than equal to 6,
给我所有大于等于 6 的键，
I could traverse down the, you know, this side of the tree, get to the bottom,
我可以沿着树的这一边遍历，到达底部，
and now I can [] through along the leaf nodes and never have to go back up,
现在我可以沿着叶子节点，不用回到上面了，
we won't talk about multi threading just yet,
我们现在还不会讨论多线程，
but like like the having to get parent lock or latches on your parents in order to scan along,
但是为了扫描而不得不获取父节点的锁，
that's gonna be expensive,
这将是昂贵的，
if I can just keep down at the lowest level I need to go,
如果我能保持在我需要去的最低层级，
then I can, I can move more quickly.
那么我可以移动得更快。
And again, if it's random I/O, this sucks,
再次，如果它是随机 I/O ，这很糟糕，
but if I get down here,
但如果我到了这里，
assuming all these pages are sequentially or contiguous on each other on disk,
假设所有这些页面都是在磁盘上彼此顺序或连续，
then that's all sequential I/O, to scan across.
那么所有这些要扫过的都是顺序 I/O 。
Yes.
是的。
Yeah, it point goes,
是的，它指向，
what's the point of having these in the inner nodes,
在内部节点中这些指向什么，
it helps you when do splits, merges, right,
它在拆分和合并时对你有帮助，
if I know I have to,
如果我知道我必须，
like if I want to steal something,
比如我想偷走某个东西，
so say if I delete 10, say 10 gets deleted,
比如，如果我删除 10 ，10 被删除，
instead of having to reorganize the entire tree,
不是必须重新组织整棵树，
I could follow sibling pointer,
我可以跟随兄弟指针，
maybe take a key from this guy and bring it over.
也许从这个节点拿出一个键，把它带过来。
Yes.
是的。
What is question,
问题是什么，
what is a node pointer,
什么是节点指针，
these red lines,
这些红色的行，
oh, the node pointer,
哦，节点指针，
I'll show the next slide,
我将播放下一张幻灯片，
you're not going to lay this out exactly,
你不会完全把这个这样放置，
you wouldn't lay this out in a disk exactly I'm describing,
你不会把这些都完全按我描述的放在磁盘上，
but to think of it is,
但是考虑它是，
like I have the key here 20,
比如我这里有键 20 ，
and so that's this part,
这就是这部分，
and then the node pointer is saying,
然后节点指针说，
if you're looking for a key that's less than 20,
如果你要寻找一个小于 20 的键，
follow this pointer and you go down here, you find it,
沿着这个指针往下走，你就会找到它，
and in an our world, in a database system that's on disk,
在我们的世界里，在磁盘上的数据库系统中，
it's just a page ID.
它只是一个页面 ID 。
Yeah, this is the visualization people usually show, show.
是的，这是人们通常的视觉化显示。
All right, so the, the nodes themselves are going to be basically arrays of key value pairs,
好的，所以节点本身基本上是键值对的数组，
and again, the keys are to be derived from whatever the attribute that the index is based on from the table,
键将从表中索引所基于的任何属性派生，
so I say I built an index on table foo column abc,
所以假设我在表 foo 列 abc 上构建了一个索引，
the key itself will be copies of the values for every single tuple in abc,
键本身将是 abc 中每个 tuple 的副本，
so you can sort of think,
所以，你可以在某种程度上认为，
the index is like a replica of the table that, that you're trying to index,
索引就是为你要索引的表的副本，
and it's, it's organized in such a way in an ordered manner,
它是以这样一种有序的方式组织的，
that allow you to do these efficient log n lookups, right,
你可以进行高效的 log n 查找，
in the relational model, the tables are could potentially be unsorteded,
在关系型模型中，表可能是未排序的，
we'll violate that in a few more slides,
我们将在几张幻灯片中违反这一点，
but the table could be unsorteded
但表可能是未排序的，
and so this index is a way to have fast sort of access.
所以索引是一种快速排序访问的方法。
And of course, now only if it covers the database system,
当然，只有在它涵盖数据库系统的情况下，
and we'll see this later in the semester,
我们将在本学期晚些时候看到这一点，
has to make sure that your index is in sync with the table, right,
必须确保你的索引与表同步，
meaning if I update, insert a tuple into my table,
意思是如果我更新，在我的表中插入 tuple ，
I want to automatically update my indexes
我想要自动更新我的索引，
and the database system will do this for you
数据库系统会为你做这件事，
and make sure everything is consistent in sync.
并确保一切都是同步的。
But again, we won't focus on that in this class.
同样，我们在这节课上不会关注这个。
The.
这个。
The values can differ depending,
这些值可能会有所不同，
the values will differ, depending on where the inner node or a leaf node,
值会不同，取决于是内部节点或叶子节点，
if it's inner node,
如果它是内部节点，
the value is a pointer to some page below us,
值是指向我们下面某个页面的指针，
if it's the leaf node,
如果它是叶子节点，
then it's gonna be either again the the pointer to the tuple,
那么它将是指向 tuple 的指针，
I'm using the pointer, not the memory address term,
我使用的指针而不是内存地址术语，
I meaning like in page, ID,
我的意思是页面 ID ，
oh, sorry the record ID or could be the actual tuple itself.
抱歉，记录 ID 可以是 tuple 本身。
The arrays within the nodes themselves are typically kept in sorted order,
节点本身中的数组通常按排序顺序保存，
but they don't have to be,
但不必如此，
and then there's this issue,
然后就有了这个问题，
how do you deal with NULL keys?
你如何处理 NULL 键？
Because again, assume that if the index are trying to build,
因为假设，如果索引尝试构建，
the index are trying to build using B+ tree,
索引尝试使用 B+ 树构建，
if if it's non unique there could be NULL values,
如果它不是唯一的，则可能有空值，
we have to put the null somewhere,
我们必须将空值放在某个地方，
so typically you either put them all at the end or all all at the beginning,
所以通常你要么把它们全部放在末尾，要么全部放在开头，
and actually when you create indexes in some systems,
实际上，当你在某些系统中创建索引时，
you actually define where you want them,
你实际上定义了想要它们的位置，
you want to be first or after,
你想要第一个还是之后，
because depending on what your query is,
因为根据查询内容的不同，
you may want to not see the nulls first,
你可能不希望首先看到空值，
you may want to see them at the end,
而可能希望在最后看到它们，
and it depends on applications.
这取决于应用程序。
Another important thing also, too, is that,
另一件重要的事情是，
going back here,
回到这里，
there's only sibling pointers and pointers going down,
只有兄弟指针和指针向下移动，
there's no pointers going back up,
没有回传的指针，
and the reason is why,
原因是，
we'll see this more next class is,
我们将在下一节课中看到更多，
when we start taking latches on these nodes,
当我们开始在这些节点上使用 latch 的时候，
we don't want to have one thread going this way, you know, from the top down,
我们不想让一个线程以这种方式运行，自上而下，
another thread going from the bottom top,
另一个线程从自下而上，
because that's going to have deadlocks,
因为这将导致死锁，
now the sibling pointers are going have this issue too,
现在兄弟指针也会有这个问题，
and we'll see how to handle that,
我们将看看如何处理这个问题，
but by avoiding having the pointers going in two directions between different levels,
但通过避免指针在不同级别之间的两个方向上移动，
it's one less thing we have to worry about.
我们需要担心的事情就少了一件。
Because we don't need,
因为我们不需要，
the way we're going to do splits and merges,
我们将要进行拆分和合并的方式，
it's not like an AVL tree,
它不像一棵 AVL 树，
where you have to do rotations and all that,
你必须做旋转和所有的事情，
we're not going do any of that.
我们不会这么做。
Some may say it's, it's easier,
可能有人会说，这更容易，
no, not really,
不，不是真的，
they both, both hard.
它们都很困难。
All, right, so here's what again our node looks like
好的，这又是我们的节点的样子，
and somewhere in assuming this is a page, right,
假设这是一个页面，
so we're going to have this array of key value pointers, sorry, keys and values,
所以我们将有这个键值指针数组，抱歉，键和值，
and then we'll have these pointers here,
然后我们在这里有这些指针，
that go, that'll be just a page ID to the previous one and to the next one
这将是前一个和下一个的页面 ID ，
along along along our level,
沿着我们的层级，
the key value pairs could either be sorted one after another,
键值对可以一个接一个地排序，
if it's a, it's an inner node,
如果它是一个内部节点，
then the values would just be pointers, again, record IDs,
那么值就只是指针，记录 ID ，
we could also sort them separately,
我们也可以分别对它们进行排序，
and this, this common approach,
这个常见的方法，
you would have the the key sort of in one array
你会把键排序放在一个数组中，
and then the values sort of separately in another array,
然后把值分别放在另一个数组中，
and then whatever offset you are in the in the, you know, in the key array
然后无论你在键数组中，
that corresponds to some offset in the in the value array,
对应于在值数组中的一些偏移量，
it's almost like the column store stuff, we said before,
它几乎就像我们之前说过的列存储的东西，
you can do simple arithmetic to decide how to jump around
你可以用简单的算术来决定如何跳过，
[], mess that up,
[]，把它搞砸，
but you you just maintain offset table to keep keep track of these things.
但是你只需要维护偏移表，跟踪这些东西。
So, and then there's additional [] keep track of,
所以，还有一个额外的[]来跟踪，
like, here's a number of slots I have left my my page,
比如，这是我的页面上留下的一些 slot ，
what level, you know, what level am I looking at,
我看的是什么层级，
and that way as you're traversing down,
当你向下遍历时，
you can just look in the page and say,
你可以只看着页面，然后说，
okay, where am I in the tree,
好的，我在树的什么位置，
it's also useful for recovery as well.
它对恢复也很有用。
So I've already said this,
所以我已经说过了，
I'm just repeating myself,
我只是重复我自己，
but the, the, the leaf node values themselves could either be record IDs,
但是，叶节点值本身可以是记录 ID ，
which is page number and offset to some location
也就是页面编号和到某个位置的偏移量，
and then the or could be a tuple data
然后可以是 tuple 数据，
as in the case of an index organized storage,
就像索引组织存储，
when we talked about before,
我们之前讨论过的，
like SQLite and MySQL do this by default,
比如 SQLite 和 MySQL 在默认情况下是这样做的，
but in like SQL Server and Oracle,
但在 SQL Server 和 Oracle 中，
you can say CREATE TABLE and I want to be index organized, right,
你可以说 CREATE TABLE ，我想要索引组织的。
and it'll, it'll make the, it'll make a B+ tree
它会生成一个 B+ 树，
and then the leaf nodes will be the actual just tuple themselves.
然后叶子节点就是 tuple 本身。
You, for the number two, you only do this for the the primary key index,
对于第二个，你只对主键索引执行这个操作，
otherwise you're duplicating data,
否则你将复制数据，
you don't want to do that.
你不会想这么做的。
Yes.
是的。
The question, if it's storing record IDs is a leaf node or inner node,
问题是，否存储记录 ID 是叶子节点还是内部节点，
it's a leaf node,
它是叶子节点，
because again.
因为。
We bring up an example in a second.
我们马上就会举一个例子。
Here the,
在这里，
the only really keys that exist,
唯一存在的键，
that actually correspond to what's actually in your table
对应于表中，
are found in the leaf nodes.
是在叶子节点中找到的。
So we'll see this in our demo,
所以，我们将在 demo 中看到这个，
when we delete and insert keys,
当我们删除和插入键时，
they the a key that was deleted may actually still exist in in an inner node, right,
被删除的键，可能仍然存在于内部节点中，
so you can't have it,
所以你不能让它，
like you couldn't have it be a record ID to point to something,
你不能让它指向某个东西的记录 ID ，
because that that record may not exist,
因为在那个记录可能不存在，
in this case, here I have in this inner node here, I have 35,
在这种情况中，我在这个内部节点里是 35 ，
but there's no 35 in the leaf node,
但叶子节点中没有 35 ，
meaning at some point,
这意味着在某个时刻，
this key got 35 inserted into it and then got deleted,
这个键插入了 35 ，然后被删除了，
but because the way it it got organized
但因为它的组织方式，
and in the algorithm to maintain the balance of the of the tree,
以及在维护树的平衡的算法中，
I didn't end up removing 35,
我最终没有删除 35 ，
so it's still there,
所以它仍然在那里，
so it's the thing like all the Internet guy posts
所以它就像互联网人发布的帖子一样，
or you know, or traffic signs or street signs
或者或者交通标志或街道标志，
to tell you how to get down to where you need to go in in the leaves.
告诉你如何在叶子中到达你需要去的地方。
Yes.
是的。
His statement is,
他的说法是，
is it true to say that every inner node has one key,
是否每个内部节点都有一个键，
but every leaf node can have multiple keys?
但是每个叶子节点可以有多个键？
This example here,
在这里的这个例子中，
I'm showing two keys per node,
我展示了每个节点的两个键，
because I got to make it fit on Powerpoint, right,
因为我必须使它适合幻灯片，
there's nothing about the B+ tree,
这里跟 B+ 树没有任何关系，
that says you can only have two keys,
说你只能有两个键，
you have multiple keys.
你可以有多个键。
In this example?
在这个例子中？
In this example, yeah, you only need one,
在这个例子中，是的，你只需要一个，
but in a real B+ tree,
但是在真正的 B+ 树中，
you wouldn't have one key for index per node, right,
你不必每个节点有一个键，
you can have unlimited, right,
你可以有无限的，
and we'll get this in a second,
我们很快就会到这里，
the slower the disk, actually, the bigger the node you want,
磁盘越慢，你想要的节点就越大，
because that's more sequential I/O,
因为这是更多的顺序 I/O ，
you could have hundreds of keys,
你可以有几百个键，
there's a limitation on what I can show on PowerPoint,
我在幻灯片上展示的内容是有限的，
but we'll bring up the demo in a second.
但我们马上会展示 demo 。
Other questions?
还有其他问题吗？
Okay, so,
好的，那么，
I made a big deal,
我做了一个大的[决定]，
like, okay, we're talking about B+ trees, not B trees,
我们说的是 B+ 树，不是 B 树，
you may not know what a B tree is.
你可能不知道什么是 B 树。
So, the original B tree from 1972
所以，源自 1972 年的原始 B 树
had all the keys and values stored all throughout the tree,
将所有键和值存储在整个树中，
like AVL tree, for example,
比如 AVL 树，
and it's more space efficient,
它更节省空间，
because you never have keys that are,
因为你从来没有键，
that don't correspond to actually something in your data set,
与你的数据库中的实际数据不一致，
like I said before,
就像我之前说的，
I could delete record 35, key 35
我可以删除记录 35 ，键 35 ，
and I get it'll get removed from the leaf nodes,
它会从叶子节点中删除，
but it may end up is still one of the guideposts,
但它最终可能仍然是一个路标，
or I could have multiple copies of the key
或者我可能有多个键的副本，
going down my inner nodes to the leaf node,
从内部节点到叶子节点，
and that's potentially wasting data or wasting space.
这可能会浪费数据或空间。
So in a B tree,
所以在一个 B 树中，
a key only appears once anywhere in the entire tree,
一个键在整个树的任何地方只出现一次，
but the problem with that one is the,
但它的问题是，
the values mean, the record pointing to the actual tuples,
这些值表示，指向实际 tuple 的记录，
they can be anywhere in the tree,
它们可以在树中的任何地方，
and so now if I want to scan along sequentially
现在如果我想按顺序扫描，
to get all the keys I need in, in, in sort of order,
得到我需要的所有键，
I may have to traverse up, up and down,
我可能需要向上，向下遍历，
because I basically have to do breadth-first search, right.
因为我基本上在做广度优先搜索。
And again, we're not going to talk about latching just yet,
再次，我们现在还不打算讨论 latch ，
but think of like, I basically have to latch the entire tree,
但是想想看，我基本上必须锁整个树，
as I'm going up and down,
因为我向上和向下移动，
whereas in a B+ tree,
而在一个 B+ 树中，
because the leaf nodes are only places where values actually are, right,
因为只有叶子节点是值实际存在的地方，
consider like, that's the, the exact copy of what's in the table,
考虑就像是表中（值）的准确副本，
once I get to the leaf nodes,
一旦我到达叶子节点，
I don't have to maintain any of the latches from upper parts in the tree,
我不需要维护树中上部的任何 latch ，
and I can just scan along the leaves
我可以沿着叶子扫描，
and let other threads do whatever they want at the top of a []
让其他线程在[]的顶部做任何它们想做的事情，
as long as doesn't need for what I'm doing, right.
而不需要我做的事情。
So the advantage for a B+ tree over B trees is that,
所以 B+ 树相对于 B 树的优势在于，
we're going to have better concurrent access,
我们有更好的并发访问，
and again, we're going to maximize,
同样，我们将最大限度地，
improve the amount of sequential I/O we're doing, over random I/O.
提高我们在顺序 I/O 的数量，而不是随机 I/O 。
Yes.
是的。
His question is,
他的问题是，
if the, if the inner nodes only, only guideposts,
如果，如果内部节点只是路标，
why do we have, why do we have sibling pointers?
为什么我们会有兄弟指针？
Because when you're doing split merges,
因为在你进行拆分合并时，
you may need to do borrow things or emerge with your neighbor,
你可能需要借东西或与你的相邻节点合并，
and they may, they may,
他们可能，
you know, you have the same parent,
你们有相同的父节点，
instead of going make it parent,
不是从父节点得到，
you can go across and get them,
你可以绕过并得到它们，
you don't need it, it's just an optimization.
你不需要它，它只是一个优化。
Postgres does it,
Postgres 实现了它，
I actually don't know, I don't know whether MySQL does.
我不知道 MySQL 是不是这样的。
So let's see,
所以让我们看看，
how we want to do our basic operations.
我们想要如何做我们的基本操作。
So do an insert,
所以，做一个 insert ，
we want to,
我们想要，
basically, the goal is to find the correct leaf node,
基本上目标是找到正确的叶子节点，
we're gonna basically traverse down, following the guidepost,
我们基本上要往下走，沿着路标，
get to some leaf node,
到达某个叶子节点，
where, where our key should be
我们的键应该在那里，
and if it has enough space,
如果它有足够的空间，
great, we insert it in,
很好，我们把它插入，
sorted, order in in that leaf node
在那个叶子节点上排序，
and we're done,
我们就完成了，
if there's not enough space,
如果没有足够的空间，
meaning the keys, the number of keys we have is full at the node,
这意味着节点上我们拥有的键的数量是满的，
then we have to split whatever the leaf node we're trying to insert into into two nodes,
那么我们必须将我们试图插入的叶子节点拆分为两个节点，
divide it in half,
把它一分为二，
but half the keys go on one side, half the keys go on the other side,
一半的键放在一边，一半的键放在另一边，
and then you're gonna copy up whatever the middle key is between in that, in that list of keys up to your parent,
然后你要复制列表中间的键到你的父节点，
and then now we have a new new new guidepost
现在我们有了一个新的路标
and a new pointer down to the new the new node, you just created,
和一个指向你刚刚创建的新节点的新指针，
new leaf node.
新的叶子节点。
And of course, this happens recursively, right,
当然，这是递归发生的，
if I, if I, if I promote up the middle key that I split on to the parent
如果我把中间的键向上提升到父节点，
and that parent is full,
而父节点是满的，
well, now I gotta split the parent,
那么现在我必须拆分父节点，
and that can cascade all the way to the top.
而这可能会一直延续到顶端。
So, making, making these slides show this in, in PowerPoint,
所以，在 PowerPoint 中制作这些幻灯片来展示这个，
it's kind of pain,
是一种痛苦，
so, I'm going to do,
所以，我要做的，
I'm going to bring up this visualization,
我要把这个可视化，
so this is a,
所以这是一个，
bring it up here,
把它拿到这里，
the size, here we go,
这是我们要的大小，
so this is a website,
这是一个网站，
the link on the slides takes you to the wrong one,
幻灯片上的链接将你带到错误的地址，
I'll update it,
我会更新它，
but if you search B+ tree visualization,
但如果你搜索 B+ 树可视化，
you'll get this.
你会得到这个。
So, I'm going to do a demo of a B+ tree, with degree 2,
所以我要做一个 B+ 树的 demo ，阶数是 2 ，
so the maximum number of keys per node is 2,
所以每个节点的最大键数是 2 ，
and maximum of pointers is going to be 3.
最大指针数是 3 。
So the first thing we'll do,
所以我们要做的第一件事，
we're going to insert 2,
我们插入 2 ，
that lands in our root node,
它落在我们的根节点上，
can I make that bigger,
我能把它放大一点吗，
let's try this, height 200
让我们试试这个，高度 200 ，
and then now I can maybe do this,
然后现在我也许可以做这个，
is that better?
这样好点了吗？
All right, so then we're going to insert 6, right,
好的，然后我们要插入 6 ，
so again, we only have a root node,
再次，我们只有一个根节点，
it can hold two keys,
它可以容纳两个键，
so nothing changes here,
所以这里没有什么变化，
so now we're going to insert 4.
所以现在我们要插入 4 。
So in this case here,
所以，在这个例中，
we try to put three keys in our root,
我们尝试在根节点中放入三个键，
we can't do that,
我们不能这么做，
so it decides to split on 4,
所以它决定在 4 上分裂，
makes two new, two new leaf nodes
生成两个新的叶子节点，
and then the middle key is 4,
然后中间的键是 4 ，
anything less than 4 goes on this side,
任何小于 4 的在这边，
greater than 4 goes on the other side,
大于 4 的在另一边，
so 2 is on this node, over here, this leaf node,
所以 2 在这个叶子节点，
and then 4 and 8 on the other side.
然后 4 和 8 在另一边。
And in this implementation,
在这个实现中，
they only have the sibling pointer going in one direction,
它们只有一个方向的兄弟指针，
some systems do that,
有些系统这样做，
Postgres does both directions,
Postgres 做了两个方向，
and it's not wrong, it done differently.
这不是错的，只是做得不同，
So now I insert 5, right,
所以现在我插入 5 ，
so I follow 4,
我跟着插入 4 ，
4 is less than 5, is greater, greater than equal to 4,
4 小于 5 ，大于等于 4 ，
so it would go down to the previous node,
所以它将向下移动到前一个节点，
but then I have, I had two keys already in there,
但是我已经有两个键了，
so I had to split that key and split that leaf node,
所以我必须拆分那个叶子节点，
I made two nodes
我做了两个节点，
and then I I put 5 up there.
然后我把 5 放在上面。
Okay?
好的？
So first, so good?
所以第一个，（大家）都还好吗？
So, delete is essentially the reverse of this,
所以， delete 本质上是与此相反的，
where we start the root, go down
我们从根节点开始，向下移动，
until we find the leaf node where entry, the entry we want remove,
直到我们找到我们想要删除的条目，
if it's not there, then we don't do anything,
如果它不在那里，我们不会做任何事情，
because we can't delete a key that doesn't exist,
因为我们不能删除不存在的键，
if it is there, then we go ahead and delete it,
如果它在那里，那么我们继续并删除它，
so if the leaf node we just modified is at least half full,
如果我们刚刚修改的叶子节点至少有一半是满的，
then we're done,
那么我们就完成了，
we pop it out and we don't do anything,
我们抛出它，什么都不做，
but now, but if the leaf node after deleting that key, goes below our threshold, right,
但如果删除键后的叶子节点低于我们的阈值，
M, M/2-1,
M/2-1 ，
M is the number of keys per node,
M 是每个节点的键的数量，
then we have to redistribute,
那我们就得重新分配，
the first thing we try to do is redistribute
我们尝试做的第一件事是重新分配，
meaning follow the sibling pointers,
意味着跟随兄弟指针，
find a, another node at the same level as us
找到与我们相同级别的另一个节点，
and steal one of their keys,
并获取它们的一个键，
like, as long as they don't become unbalanced, that's okay,
比如，只要他们不会变得不平衡，那就没问题，
we may have to tweak up above the parent node,
我们可能不得不在父节点上方进行调整，
in the parent node, the the guideposts, the split point,
在父节点中，路标，分割点，
but again, that's's not that expensive,
但同样，这并不昂贵，
because we would already have the latch for it,
因为我们已经有了它的 latch ，
we cover next time.
我们下一次会讲到。
If we can't redistribute,
如果我们不能重新分配，
then we had to merge L with one of its siblings,
那么我们必须将 L 与其兄弟项之一合并，
combine those two keys, put it together
将这两个的键组合在一起，
and then update the parent accordingly, right.
然后相应地更新父节点。
And again, this is recursive,
再次，这是递归的，
so if I merge two, two nodes together
所以如果我将两个节点合并在一起，
and then I delete a guidepost key at my parent
然后我删除一个父节点上的路标键，
and now the parent is less than half full,
现在父节点不到一半满了，
then the merge will cascade up.
然后合并将层叠向上。
What does it feel,
如果它，
like if I, if I have two keys,
如果我有两个键，
you have one key
你有一个键，
and you're my, you're my sibling,
你是我的兄弟节点，
I delete a key
我删除了一个键，
and I less than half full,
我不到一半满了，
that's a bad example,
这是个坏例子，
because there's say three keys, right,
因为有三个键，
if you have two keys
如果你有两个键，
and I have two keys,
我有两个键，
I delete a key,
我删除一个键，
I'm like oh, I'm less than half full
我就像，哦，我没有一半满，
and I go try to steal one of your keys,
我想拿走你的一个键，
but if I do that to you,
但如果我这么做了，
then you're less than half full,
你就没一半满了，
so I can't.
所以我不能。
All right, so let's go back to our demo.
好的，让我们回到我们的 demo 。
All right, so,
好的，所以，
we can go ahead and delete,
我们可以继续并删除，
so let's go ahead and delete 8,
所以让我们继续并删除 8 ，
8 at the far end here,
8 在这里最远的一端，
it was 6, sorry,
它是 6 ，抱歉，
6, right, goes over here, delete 6,
6 ，在这里，删除 6 ，
that's fine, we're still balanced,
这是好的，我们仍然是平衡的，
it's two keys, two keys per node, still half full,
每个节点两个键，仍然是半满的，
in this case, 1,
在这种情况下，是 1 ，
we can go, we can go to degree 4, that look better,
我们可以去 4 阶，它看起来更好，
but now I say I delete key 4 in the middle, right,
但现在说我要删除中间的键 4 ，
it basically propagates up and removes it from above.
它基本上向上传播，并将其从上方移除。
So let's go to degree 4,
所以让我们来看看 4 阶，
because then you can start seeing the stealing better.
因为这样你就可以更好地看到偷取行为。
So let's do the same thing to insert 1,
所以让我们做同样的事情来插入 1 ，
insert 2, 4 5,
插入 2 4 5 ，
split, now we got there,
分裂，现在我们到了这里，
6 8,
6 8 ，
and then we do 9.
然后我们插入 9 。
So we're going to go ahead and delete 5 in the middle here,
所以，我们将继续，删除这里中间的 5 ，
and again, at this point here,
再次，在这里，
this node, this leaf node will become less than half full,
这个叶子节点将变得不到一半满，
so the first thing we try to do is
所以我们要做的第一件事就是，
try to steal from, from when its siblings,
试着从它的兄弟节点那里偷取，
so let's go ahead and delete 5,
所以，让我们继续并删除 5 ，
didn't do that,
没有那么做，
why not?
为什么不是？
Yeah.
是的。
What is that.
是什么？
Yeah, I think it's a 4,
是的，我想是 4 ，
so I delete 4, see what it does,
所以我删除 4 ，看看它是怎么做的，
yeah, there steals.
是的，那里有偷取。
Yeah, so this animation doesn't follow the textbook exactly,
是的，所以这个动画并不是完全按照教科书，
but like, it's, it's not wrong,
但它是没有错的，
it's just like different ways to do things,
这就像是做事情的不同方式，
like, you know, how aggressive you want to be on certain optimizations,
就像，你想在某些优化上有多积极，
but as long as you get the high level idea, that you could steal.
但是你得到了高层次想法，你可以偷取。
But you still have to update the parent, when you steal,
但当你偷取时，你仍然必须更新父节点，
because that's going to change the boundary points.
因为这将更改边界点。
Yes.
是的。
In this example here,
在这个例中，
they have siblinginters going one direction,
它们有单向的同级指针，
Postgres and other systems go in both directions, double linked list.
Postgres 和其他系统有双向的链表。
Yes.
是的。
Yeah, his question is,
是的，他的问题是，
actually, I had an example of that,
事实上，我有一个这样的例子，
actually, that's a question,
有个问题，
actually, I don't have an example of that,
实际上，我没有这样的例子，
well, I know I do in the middle here,
好的，我知道我在这中间做的，
these guys,
这些家伙，
I, yeah, so I think the leaf nodes,
是的，所以我认为叶子节点，
you definitely want pointers to your siblings along this,
你肯定想要指针指向你的兄弟节点，
because you need to go along the leaf nodes,
因为你需要沿着叶子节点前进，
if this guy had like, you know, this thing got even bigger,
如果这家伙变得更大了，
could you have two parents,
你能有两个父节点吗，
could two, two, two nodes at the same level had pointed to each other
两个同一级别上的节点必须指着对方，
even though they was, you know, have the same parent,
即使它们有相同的父节点，
you could, I don't know,
你可以，我不知道，
actually, I don't know what Postgres does or other systems do.
事实上，我不知道 Postgres 做了什么或其他系统做了什么。
To this point, you may not,
在这一点上，你可能不会，
so if you had the same parent, or.
所以，如果你有相同的父节点，还是。
Everyone comes up to the root, like,
每个节点都来自根节点，就像，
it may be a case you have to, like, reorganize everything, right,
这可能是一个，你必须重新组织一切，
so that may help,
所以这可能会有帮助，
but at that point, you're latching the whole tree, so who cares?
但在这一点上，你在锁住整棵树，谁在乎呢？
Yes.
是的。
This question is,
这个问题是，
if you don't, if you don't store a pointer to the parent,
如果你不存储指向父节点的指针，
how do you send data to the parent.
如何将数据发送到父节点？
We will discuss this next class,
我们将在下一节课中讨论，
because basically, as you're going down,
因为基本上，当你向下时，
you keep track of the stack of the nodes you visit as you go down,
你将跟踪你在向下时访问的节点堆栈，
and you keep track of which ones you had the latch for,
并跟踪你为哪些节点设置了 latch ，
so I can go down,
如果我向下，
if I'm traversing down here,
如果我从这里向下，
and say this guy here, I have to, I gotta split,
然后比如这个家伙，我必须分裂，
when I, when I come down, and get here,
当我下来的时候，到了这里，
I would recognize,
我就会意识到，
hey, I'm gonna have to split,
嘿，我要分裂了，
don't release the latch of my parent,
不要释放我的父节点的 latch ，
so I still have a pointer,
所以我还有一个指针，
I still have it on my stack,
我还把它放在我的堆栈上，
I can get back to.
我可以回去看看。
So it's the internal bookkeeping of the worker
所以，这是 worker 的内部[簿记]，
as it goes down the threads or goes down the tree.
当它沿着树向下。
Yes, again.
是的，再次。
And so we'll talk about it means be safer, unsafe, traversals,
所以我们将谈论它意味着更安全，更不安全，
like, you know, like, as you go down, if you would know,
比如，当你往下的时候，你会知道，
I'm, I'm trying to delete something,
我在试着删除一些东西，
so as I go down,
所以当我往下时，
if I know that no matter whether or not,
如果我知道，不管如何，
the key m need need below me, whether it's there or not,
我下面的键 m ，不管它在哪里，
I know that, there I won't have to do a merge or split on this node,
我知道我不需要对这个节点进行合并或拆分，
what I'm at right now,
我所在的节点，
so once I go past it, I don't. I can release the latch on it,
所以一旦我过了它，我可以释放它的 latch ，
could it's considered safe, it won't,
它被认为是安全的，它不会，
No matter what happens below you,
不管你下面发生什么，
it'll never get reorganized,
它永远不会重新组织，
so you don't need to maintain the last [word].
所以你不需要保留最后一个[字]。
That will cover next class.
这将在下一节课中讲到。
All right, so that's the basic operations for splits emerges,
好的，这就是分裂、合并的基本操作，
so the B+ tree,
所以 B+ 树，
just trees in general,
只是一般的树，
B+ tree from B+ in, in databases
在数据库中， B+ 树，
is gonna have a bunch of, do a bunch of other stuff,
将会有一堆其他的东西，
we can we, we couldn't be able, we couldn't do with a hash table.
我们不能用哈希表。
So a hash table, the only operation we could do is,
所以哈希表，我们唯一能做的操作就是，
something equals this key, right,
某个东西等于这个键，
is the, is the hash key equal to my to my key I'm looking up on,
哈希键是否等于我要找的键，
we can't do less than, we can't do greater than
我们不能做小于，我们不能做大于，
and we can't do any partial key lookup,
我们不能做任何部分键查找，
you have to have the entire key, right.
你必须拥有完整的键。
So if I say,
所以，如果我说，
I build an index on columns a b c,
我在列 a b c 上构建索引，
I if I only have columns a and b, for my key,
如果对于我的键，我只有列 a 和 b ，
I can't hash that and jump to anything meaningful, right,
我不能哈希它并跳到任何有意义的地方，
because the hash is completely random.
因为哈希是完全随机的。
But in B+ tree,
但是在 B+ 树中，
we can do a bunch of tricks,
我们可以做一系列的技巧，
where we can potentially only have, or not potentially you can,
我们可能只拥有，或者不可能，
you can only have parts of the key
你只能拥有部分键，
or a certain number of the attributes, that your key is based on
或者基于你的键的特定数量的属性，
and still use it for queries.
并且仍然将其用于查询。
So again, say index on a b c,
再次，比如说 a b c 的索引，
so obviously, I can do a=1, b=2 and c=3,
所以很明显，我可以做 a=1 b=2 c=3 ，
that's the same thing as the hashing,
这和哈希是一样的，
I have the [quality] matching for all of the keys,
我有[质量]匹配的所有键，
that are in my, that, that the index is based on.
都在我的，索引所基于的。
I also can do what's called a prefix search,
我也可以做所谓的前缀搜索，
where I only have a and b and not c, right,
我只有 a 和 b ，没有 c ，
and we can do the lookup
我们可以进行查找，
to define all the matches based on the a and b without c.
定义所有匹配，基于 a 和 b ，而不包括 c 。
But we'd also, not all systems do this,
但我们也，不是所有的系统都这样做，
because it's trickier to do,
因为这样做更棘手，
but we also can do a suffix look up,
但我们也可以做后缀搜索，
where we don't have the prefix,
我们没有前缀，
we have the suffix of the keys,
我们有键的后缀，
so I don't have a, but I have b and c
所以我没有 a ，但我有 b 和 c ，
and I can potentially still use my index and do that lookup,
我仍然可以使用我的索引，进行查找，
very few systems do this, this is hard,
很少有系统做这个，这太难了，
Postgres doesn't do this,
Postgres 没有这么做，
the Oracle and I think maybe SQL Server can do this.
Oracle ，我认为也许 SQL Server 可以做这个。
All right?
好的？
And again, if it was a hash index,
再次，如果它是哈希索引，
we have to have the entire key
我们必须拥有整个键，
and it always has to be in [quality predicate].
并且它必须始终在[质量谓词]中。
Yeah, because you basically need to have like potentially multiple threads at the same time going down
因为你基本上需要可能多个线程同时向下，
and everyone, everyone coordinating,
每个线程协调，
there might be a patent from Oracle,
Oracle 可能有一个专利，
and that present people from doing this,
禁止人们这样做，
wouldn't surprise me, I don't know,
不会让我感到惊讶，我不知道，
they're called skip scans at Oracle
它们在 Oracle 被称为跳跃扫描，
and that that might be why nobody does. Nobody else does this.
这可能是为什么没有人这样做的原因。
Alright, so again,
好的，再次，
say I have my my index on a and b,
我在 a 和 b 上有我的索引，
if I want to find key 1 and 2,
如果我想找到键 1 和 2 ，
again I use my guide posts
再次，我使用我的路标，
and essentially just looking at the keys,
基本上只是查看键，
the the parts of the key in in sort of sequential order,
以顺序模式键的各个部分，
so first I check is 1 less, less than equal to 1
所以，首先我检查的是 1 小于等于 1 ，
and then I check the second part is 2 less than equal to 3
然后我检查第二部分是 2 小于等于 3 ，
and that tells me that I want to follow down this to this, this node here
这告诉我我想沿着这个节点往下，
and then I can find the entry I'm looking for.
然后我就可以找到我寻找的条目。
If I'm doing a prefix search,
如果我进行前缀搜索，
meaning I have the first part of the key but not the remaining part,
意味着我有键的第一部分，但没有剩下的部分，
so I have key on a, but not b,
所以我有 a 的键，但是没有 b ，
the way that would work is,
这样做的方法是，
you basically look at the part that you do have
你基本上查看你有的部分，
and see is 1 less equal to 1,
然后看 1 是否小于等于 1 ，
yes, follow down here
是的，继续往下走，
and then now I scan along
然后我继续扫描，
and keep, keep evaluating my predicate
继续计算我的[谓词]，
against all the keys that are in the leaf nodes
对于叶子节点中的所有键，
until I have something that violates,
直到我有违反的东西，
or I know that 1 is now is less than 2
或者我知道现在 1 小于 2 ，
and I can't, I can't traverse here,
我不能遍历这里，
because it's a sort of order,
因为这是一种顺序，
I know there will be never, never anything,
我知道那里永远不会有任何东西，
where you know, with a key, the first part, a equals 1
有一个键，第一部分 a 等于 1 ，
and something else for b,
b 后面有其他的东西，
after at this point,
在这个点之后，
because they're sort of first on, on the first part of the key.
因为它们是键的第一部分。
Again, the last one for the skip scans,
同样，最后一个用于跳跃扫描，
basically what happens is
基本上发生的是，
you, at every single node you evaluate,
在每个节点上，你评估，
okay, what part of the key do I have,
好的，我有键的哪一部分，
and then determine what portion of the trees below you have to look at,
然后确定你必须看下面树的哪一部分，
and this is an example here,
这是一个例子，
since I don't have the first part of the key,
因为我没有键的第一部分，
I essentially have to look at everything.
我基本上必须查看所有东西。
And again, I think in Oracle,
同样，我认为在 Oracle 中，
they can have multiple threads in parallel
他们可以让多个线程并行，
go down different parts of the tree,
沿着树的不同部分，
and then they combine the results together at the end,
然后在最后将结果组合在一起，
it's almost like doing a wild card search,
这就像是在进行通配符搜索，
and so, we'll see this a little bit at the demo at the end.
我们最终将在 demo 中看到这个，
There's this trade off between in the data set,
在数据集中有这样的权衡，
it's going to make that like,
它会让它变得，
it could say, all right, well,
它可能会说，好的，
I know something about the statistics of of the keys that my index is based on,
我知道一些关于我的索引所基于的键的统计数据，
so it probably still is worth me to go look, look in the key, look in the index,
所以可能仍然值得我去看看键，看看索引，
but it may decide,
但它可能决定，
okay, well I don't know anything about what you're trying to ask me to do,
好的，我不知道你想让我做什么，
so I'm, the index is not going to help me,
所以索引不会帮助我，
I'm just gonna do a sequential scan across the entire table.
我要对整张表做一个顺序扫描。
And that actually may be faster than
这可能快于，
trying to do multiple probes down to the index
尝试对索引进行多个探测，
and combine results together.
并将结果组合在一起。
And again, it's not something the programmer has to deal with,
再次，这不是程序员必须处理的事情，
this is something we take the SQL query
这是我们使用 SQL 查询，
and try to figure this out on our own.
并尝试自己解决这个。
Again, we cover this [].
再次，我们在[]讨论这个。
Yes.
是的。
This question, this question is,
这个问题是，
is it up to the program decide what indexes to make,
是不是由程序来决定建立什么样的索引，
most systems, yes.
大多数系统，是的。
So this is, this is an old problem in databases,
所以，这是数据库中的一个老问题，
I talk about how great the abstraction is for relational model,
我谈到关系模型的抽象有多棒，
that you don't have to worry about how things are actually physically stored and all that,
你不必担心东西实际上是如何物理存储的等等，
but the end of the day,
但是最终，
someone's got to decide what indexes you actually need,
总得有人来决定你到底需要什么样的索引，
and so there's a long line of research myself here at CMU,
所以我自己在 CMU 有一长串的研究，
but like, going back to the 1970s,
但是，回到 1970 年代，
of people trying to figure out automatically what index is you need,
人们试图自动找出你想要什么索引，
and so the commercial systems have built in tools
所以，商业系统内置了工具，
that can help you figure this out,
可以帮助你解决这一问题，
MySQL and Postgres do not have that,
MySQL 和 Postgres 没有这个，
Postgres will build whatever indexes you tell it you want it,
Postgres 将构建你告诉它需要的任何索引，
do it for you, right,
为你做这些，
so you want,
所以你想，
if you tell I want a thousand indexes,
如果你告诉，我想要一千个索引，
it do it, right,
它就会这样做，
in, in SQL Server on, on Azure,
在 Azure 的 SQL Server 中，
what they actually do is,
它们实际上所做的是，
they'll spin up a separate instance for your database system,
它们为你的数据库系统启动一个单独的实例，
try out basically some kind of machine algorithm
尝试某种基本的机器算法，
to figure out what indexes you actually need
来找出你实际需要的索引，
and then suggest them to you, right,
然后向你推荐它们，
SQL Server does other other interesting things too,
SQL Server 还做了其他有趣的事情，
although in the query optimizer,
尽管在查询优化器中，
which we'll talk about after midterm,
我们将在期中之后讨论，
your query shows up,
你的查询会出现，
it starts planning it based on whatever indexes you have,
它会开始根据你拥有的任何索引来计划它，
but at some point you can also say,
但在某种程度上，你也可以说，
man, I'd be really great,
伙计，这很好，
if I had, if I had an index on this tree on this table right now,
如果我现在有一个索引在这个树上，在这个表上，
it doesn't can build it for you if potentially,
它可能不能为你构建它，
but instead of saying it can potentially build for you just for that query,
它可能可以只为那个查询构建，
but it also come back and tell you,
但它也会回来告诉你，
hey, by the way,
嘿，顺便说一句，
if you gave me this index, I'd run a lot faster.
如果你给我这个索引，我会跑得更快。
The reason why you may necessarily,
你可能必须的原因，
you know, you could build it just for the query and then throw it away,
你可以只为查询构建它，然后丢弃它，
because that only affect that query,
因为这只会影响该查询，
you may not want to build it and then keep it around,
你可能不想构建它，然后保留它，
because as I said, you got to maintain it,
因为正如我所说的，你必须维护它，
you got to keep it in sync with the table,
你必须使其与表保持同步，
so you don't want your database sort of adding like a ton of indexes
所以你不希望你的数据库添加大量索引，
and now that's gonna make all my insert updates and deletes go slower.
这将使我的所有插入、更新和删除变得更慢。
Also, too, like, you know, they take storage space, take memory space,
此外，它们占用存储空间、内存空间，
there's a cost of physical hardware as well,
还有物理硬件的成本，
that's a whole other hornets nest,
这完全是另一个马蜂窝，
we can get into.
我们可以进入。
Okay.
好的。
So the next thing we've got to deal with is,
所以，我们接下来要处理的事情是，
at this point, we know how do inserts, updates, deletes,
在这一点上，我们知道如何做插入、更新和删除，
we know to do inserts and deletes,
我们知道做插入和删除，
we know how to do basic lookup
我们知道如何进行基本的查找
to find the keys we're looking for,
来找到我们寻找的键，
whether prefix searches, full key searches or the skip scans.
无论是前缀搜索、全键搜索还是跳跃扫描。
The next challenge we got to deal with is how do we handle duplicate keys?
我们要处理的下一个挑战是如何处理重复的键？
So there's two approaches to do this.
所以，有两种方法可以做到这个。
Again, the issue is going to be like,
再说一次，问题会是这样的，
since I want to be able to,
因为我希望能够，
have everything always in log(n), right,
让每件事都是 log(n) ，
how do I actually want to handle,
我该如何处理，
have the capability of inserting keys duplic keys over and over again
有能力一遍又一遍地插入键和复制键，
and not violate that requirement.
而不违反这一要求。
So the most common approach is
所以，最常见的方法是，
to to maintain sort of a hidden column or hidden attribute in the key
在键中维护某种隐藏列或隐藏属性，
with the record ID of the tuple that it's pointing to,
其中包含它所指向的 tuple 的记录 ID ，
and then that guarantees that every key ends up being unique, right,
然后，这保证了每个键最终都是唯一的，
if you have a key on 4,
如果你有一个键在 4 上，
and I have a key on 4,
我有一个键在 4 上，
but you have a separate tuple, I have a separate tuple,
但是你有一个 tuple ，我有一个 tuple ，
if we put our, our basic, our record ID as part of the key
如果我们把我们的记录 ID 作为键的一部分，
in addition to the column based on their index,
除了基于他们的索引的列，
then your 4, my 4 end up being unique.
那么你的 4 ，我的 4 ，最终是唯一的。
And because I can do that prefix search,
因为我可以做前缀搜索，
where I don't have to have all the elements of the key to do lookups,
我不需要拥有键的所有元素来进行查找，
then this scheme still works.
所以这个方案仍然有效。
The other approach is to overload, overflow leaf nodes
另一种方法是溢出叶子节点，
and basic idea is that,
基本思想是，
the the leaf nodes themselves,
叶子节点本身，
if I, if I get too full,
如果我太满，
but I know I'm inserting the same key,
但我知道我插入的是相同的键，
then I just potentially keep building a linked list
那么我可能会继续构建一个链表，
and I sort of go down in in the depth of the tree,
我会再次深入树的深处，
again, but that violates our, our log(n) approach, our, log(n) guarantee.
但这违反了我们的 log(n) 保证。
All right, so here's how we do the record,
好的，所以这就是我们如何做记录，
so the key now isn't just number 1,
现在的键不只是数字 1 ，
it's one, and then followed by the record ID,
它是 1 ，然后跟着是记录 ID ，
which is the page number and offset.
也就是页码和偏移量。
So now if I want to insert 6
所以现在，如果我想插入 6 ，
and 6 already exists,
而 6 已经存在，
well, any time, even though you might call in SQL, INSERT 6,
那么，任何时候，即使你可能调用 SQL ， INSERT 6 ，
where the database is going to do is convert that to
数据库做的就是将其转换为，
insert 6, followed by the page number and slot number.
插入 6 ，后面跟着页码和 slot 编号。
So now when I get down here,
所以现在当我向下的时候，
since this guy is full,
因为这个节点已经满了，
I'll just do a split, slide over and.
我做一个分裂，滑动。
So things slide over
所以节点滑动过去，
and then now I can insert 6 right here, right.
现在我可以在这里插入 6 。
Again, superficially, it looks like it's like a duplicate keys,
从表面上看，它像是一个重复键，
but again, the actual bits themselves are are unique.
但是，实际的位本身是唯一的。
Of course, now if I want, if I want to do a delete on 6
当然，现在如果我想要再次删除 6 ，
again, I would have to,
我将不得不，
you know, internally the database system is gonna know,
在内部，数据库系统将知道，
okay, well, delete on 6, followed by this record ID and offset, the page number offset.
好的，删除 6 跟着这个记录 ID 和页面偏移量，
Yes.
是的。
Question, what happens if the key is not a number,
问题是，如果键不是数字会发生什么，
what do you mean?
你是什么意思？
So yeah, so 6 is the key.
所以，是的， 6 是键。
Because I insert into a table
因为我插入到一个表中，
and the table has has an index on column foo, column a,
那个表在列 foo ，列 a 上有一个索引，
and the tuple I'm inserting for that attribute sets the value to 6, right,
我插入那个属性的 tuple 将值设置为 6 ，
but instead of just putting 6 in,
但是不是只放入 6 ，
it's going to say I've already inserted into the table,
它会说，我已经插入了表中，
now I have a record ID,
现在我有了一个记录 ID ，
so when I insert into the index,
所以当我插入索引时，
it's the 6, appended by the bits for the record ID,
它是 6 ，跟着记录 ID 的位，
and that guarantees that no, many times I insert 6,
这保证了很多次我插入 6 ，
it's unique, right
它是唯一的，
now, if if it's a unique index,
如果它是唯一索引，
I, like a primary key index,
比如主键索引，
or I can declare that it's a unique index,
或者我可以声明它是唯一索引，
then I don't want to do this,
那么我不想这样做，
but the mechanism still works.
但这一机制仍然有效。
His statement is,
他的说法是，
and he's correct,
他是正确的，
this is just essentially a hidden attribute,
这本质上是一个隐藏的属性，
that guarantees that that duplicate keys are physically unique,
保证了重复键在物理上是唯一的，
because it's the record ID,
因为它是记录 ID ，
yes, that's the trick.
是的，这是个技巧。
So the overflow, overflow leaf nodes look like this,
所以，溢出叶子节点如下所示，
I insert 6,
我插入 6 ，
I recognize it's full in my leaf node,
我发现它在我的叶子节点上已经满了，
but I also recognize that,
但我也认识到，
the thing you're trying to insert already exists in here
你试图插入的东西已经存在于这里，
and therefore it's a duplicate,
因此它是一个重复的，
so I just make this overflow page and insert it down here, right,
所以我做了这个溢出页面，并将其插入到这里。
and I keep inserting new things
我不断地插入新的东西，
and I keep appending it along like this.
我一直像这样追加它。
So this looks similar to the chain hash table before,
所以，这看起来类似于前面的链哈希表，
that like,
就像是，
instead of having a hash function tell me where I land at the start of my linked list,
不是让哈希函数告诉我我在链表的开始位置，
I have a tree structure in front of it,
而是在它前面有一个树结构，
but essentially doing the same thing,
但本质上做的是相同的事情，
of course, now, again, this violates log(n),
当然，现在，再一次，这违反了 log(n) ，
we have to deal with like,
我们必须处理，
what if we actually want to split and merge,
如果我们真的想要拆分和合并，
what do we move things,
我们要移动什么东西，
this makes things way more complicated than the record ID approach, very,
这使得事情比记录 ID 方法复杂得多，
I don't think any real system actually does this.
我不认为任何真正的系统会做到这个。
The question is, what's the benefit of this approach,
问题是，这种方法的好处是什么，
now I don't need to store the record ID, right,
现在，我不需要保存记录 ID ，
duplicate, store a part in every single key,
在每个键中保存一部分，
it's potentially easier engineering,
这可能是更容易的工程设计，
actually, not really, it makes it harder.
事实上，不是很清楚，这让它变得更难了。
Yeah, this is a bad idea, don't do this,
是的，这是个坏想法，别这么做，
but you could,
但是你可以，
and so you have, I'm saying bad.
所以你可以，它是坏的。
I want to talk about cluster indexes,
我想谈谈聚集索引，
these aren't,
这些不是，
I mean, it's good for you guys at least know this,
我是说，至少你们知道这个对你们是有好处的，
this exists,
这是存在的，
but I don't want to spend too much time on it.
但我不想在上面花费太多时间，
The basic idea is that,
其基本思想是，
there's some database systems let you define what are called clustered indexes on tables,
有一些数据库系统允许你在表上定义所谓的聚集索引，
where you can allow the the actual table itself, the actual tuples themselves,
你可以允许实际的表本身，实际的 tuple 本身，
even though the relational models unsorted,
即使关系型模型没有排序，
you can say I want the physical tuples on disk to be sorted,
你可以说我希望磁盘上的物理 tuple 排序，
based on the sort order defined by some index.
基于某个索引定义的排序。
And in this case here,
在这个例子中，
if I have a true clustered index,
如果我有一个真正的聚集索引，
that no matter where I insert a new record,
无论我在哪里插入新记录，
the actual heap files themselves will be guaranteed to be in that sort of order,
实际的堆文件本身都将保证按这种顺序排序，
you sort of think of this again,
你可以再次考虑这个，
the MySQL SQLite approach,
MySQL SQLite 方法，
where the leaf nodes are actually stored the tuples,
叶子节点实际存储了 tuple ，
that's automatically clustered index,
这是自动聚集索引，
but in some database systems,
但在一些数据库系统中，
where it isn't an in organized table,
它不是一个有组织的表，
you can have the sort of be enforced by, by this kind of index, right.
你可以通过这种索引来强制执行。
And so the advantage of this is that,
这样做的好处是，
when I start doing,
当我开始这样做，
when I want to start doing scans,
当我想要开始扫描时，
assuming I'm not doing index, organized storage,
假设我不是在进行索引、有组织的存储，
when I scan along the leaf nodes
当我沿着叶子节点扫描，
to find all the tuples I'm looking for,
以找到我正在寻找的所有 tuple ，
then I'm guaranteed to get the pages,
那么我肯定会得到页面，
in sorted order based as defined on the key order, right.
在键定义的排序基础上。
So again as I scan this going across,
所以，当我再一次扫描的时候，
I get all my entries
我得到了我所有的条目，
and I get all my pages
我得到了我所有的页面，
and I [rip] through that sequentially and things go fast.
我按顺序[撕开]它，事情变得很快。
If you don't have a cluster index,
如果你没有聚集索引，
then you end up sometimes with a bunch of random I/O,
那么你有时会得到一堆随机 I/O ，
the, again the leaf nodes that could be stored sequentially on disk,
再次，叶子节点可以按顺序存储在磁盘上，
but when I start doing lookups to get the actual data, that the leaf nodes are pointing to,
但当我开始查找以获得叶子节点所指向的实际数据时，
that could end up being random, right.
最终可能是随机的。
And so if I do something really stupid,
所以，如果我做了一些非常愚蠢的事情，
like say I have one free frame in my buffer pool
比如我的缓冲池中有一个空闲的 frame ，
and if I scan along in the order,
如果我按顺序扫描，
if I fetch the page in the order that they come out of the index,
如果我按照页面从索引中出来的顺序获取页面，
I may end up doing a bunch of the redundant I/O,
我可能会得到一大堆冗余的 I/O ，
where like I fetch the page in, process on it,
比如获取页面，在它上面运行，
because that's the key I'm looking at right now
因为这是我现在正在查看的键，
or that that I got pointed to
或者我指向的，
and then I throw it away, get the next page,
然后我扔掉它，获得下一页，
but then a few few more keys later,
但是再几个键之后，
I go fetch the same page I did before.
我会获取之前相同的页面。
So a really simple optimization to do this is that,
所以，有一个非常简单的优化方法是，
you don't actually, you don't retrieve the tuples as you scan along the leaf nodes,
当你沿着叶子节点扫描时，你不会检索到 tuple ，
as you find them,
当你查找它们时，
you first do the scan the leaf nodes first,
你首先扫描叶子节点，
get your list of all your pages,
获取所有页面的列表，
then sort them in by based on page ID
然后根据页面 ID 对它们进行排序，
and then go retrieve them based on this,
然后根据这个进行检索，
now you still have to do the bookkeeping
现在你仍然需要[记账]，
to make sure that you you're following along the tuples
以确保你跟随 tuple ，
in the order defined by the index,
按照索引定义的顺序，
that that's what you care about.
这就是你所关心的。
But again, this is a way to get more sequencial I/O
同样，这是一种获得更多顺序 I/O ，
and reduce the amount of random access.
并减少随机访问量的方法。
And so, so his statement is,
所以，所以他的说法是，
why couldn't I just keep track of what I've already fetched in page,
为什么我不能跟踪我已经获取的页面，
I don't fetch it again.
然后我不再获取它。
I was giving a toy example,
我举了一个玩具例子，
where, like I only have one frame,
比如，我只有一个 frame ，
so I can only fetch one page,
所以我只能获取一页，
I throw it out and get the next page,
我把它扔掉，然后获取下一页，
in this, in this toy example.
在这个玩具例子中。
But, but think in a real system,
但是，考虑在一个真实的系统中，
again, don't think of like one page,
不要考虑一页，
think like I can have maybe, you know, 10 gigabytes of space,
考虑，比如我可能有 10G 的空间，
but my database is 1 terabyte, table is one terabyte,
但我的数据库是 1TB ，表是 1TB ，
and then you're run out of space.
然后你就会耗尽空间。
You, you want to sort them
你想要对它们进行排序，
and you want to get them in page,
你想让它们出现在页面上，
you, you want to access them in the order that they exist physically on disk
你想要以它们在磁盘上的物理存在的顺序来访问它们，
and then still do, but just bookkeeping
然后仍然这样做，只是记账，
to make sure that the order of the results you're generating
以确保你生成的结果的顺序
match the sort order of the of the index,
与的索引中排序顺序相匹配，
again to reduce amount of wasted I/O.
再次，为了减少浪费 I/O 的数量。
Okay.
好的。
So I want to quickly go through some design choices here,
所以我想在这里快速介绍一些设计选择，
how to handle certain things.
如何处理某些事情。
And so a lot of these ideas come from this book,
所以这些想法很多都来自这本书，
which is considered the Bible of B+ trees
这本书被认为是 B+ 树的圣经，
from this guy Goetz Graefe,
来自 Goetz Graefe 这个人，
he's invented a bunch of various techniques,
他发明了一系列不同的技术，
that we'll discuss this semester.
我们将在本学期讨论。
And again, it's called modern B B tree techniques,
再次，这被称为现代 B 树技术，
and again, he's about B+ trees,
再说一次，他说的是 B+ 树，
but he calls it a B tree,
但他称之为 B 树，
and actually, if you just Google this name of this book,
事实上，如果你在 Google 上搜索这本书的名字，
it's came out 2010,
它是 2010 年出版的，
it's a great book,
这是一本很棒的书，
covers a lot of these techniques and, and even more,
涵盖了很多这些技巧，甚至更多，
if you just Google, you'll find the PDF,
如果你用 Google 搜索，你会找到 PDF ，
if you like this kind of stuff,
如果你喜欢这种东西，
it's a good read.
这是一本很好的读物。
Again, because it's theory,
因为它是理论，
here's how actually you how to implement it in a real system.
这是如何在实际系统中实现它的方法。
All right, the first question is,
好的，第一个问题是，
what's going to be the node size.
节点的大小是多少。
So you can assume,
所以，你可以假设，
in all our diagrams here,
在这里的所有图表中，
one node corresponds to one page
一个节点对应于一个页面，
in, in, in, in in our in our database files, in our buffer pool,
在我们的数据库文件中，在我们的缓冲池中，
but in some systems, like in IBM DB2,
但在某些系统中，例如在 IBM DB2 中，
you can actually modify,
你实际上可以修改，
you configure the size of a database page for different tables and different indexes.
你为不同的表和不同的索引配置数据库页的大小。
And so, depending on what your hardware is,
所以，根据硬件的不同，
you may want to set the size,
你可能希望设置大小，
the page size of your B+ tree nodes differently,
B+ 树节点的页面大小不同，
and so again, the, the slower your disk,
所以，磁盘速度越慢，
typically the larger the page you want,
通常你想要的页面越大，
because it's going to be better for maximizing sequential I/O.
因为这将更有利于最大化顺序 I/O 。
So if you're an an old spinning disk hard drive,
所以，如果你是一个旧的旋转磁盘硬盘，
you want to page size of like 1 megabyte,
你想要页面大小大约为 1 兆字节，
now, the number of keys will be that you can fit on 1 megabyte page,
现在，键的数量适应 1 兆字节，
will be defined the size your keys are, right,
将被定义你的键的大小，
if they're all 8 bit integers,
如果它们都是 8 位整数，
then you can store a lot of them,
那么你可以存储很多它们，
probably more, more than you actually can have.
可能比你实际拥有的更多。
But for fast SSD,
但是对于快速的 SSD ，
it's roughly 8 to 10 kilobytes is considered to be the right size,
它大约是 8 到 10 千字节被认为是合适的大小，
and then if you're in-memory,
如果你是在内存中，
512 -} bytes is, is considered the right sizes
512 个字节被认为是合适的大小，
within a cache line,
在一个缓存行中，
you keep things very efficient, right.
你让事情变得非常高效。
We talked about that,
我们讨论了，
that some systems can actually violate that requirement,
一些系统实际上可能会违反这一要求，
that every node has to be half full,
每个节点都必须是半满的，
obviously, you can't go to more,
显然，你不能更多，
can't have more keys than you actually store,
不能拥有比你实际存储的更多的键，
because you run out of space,
因为你的空间用完了，
but you can recognize that,
但你能认出这个，
okay, well, most the,
好的，大部分，
maybe I don't want to split,
也许我不想拆分，
or maybe I want to merge my nodes all the time
或者我想一直合并我的节点，
and I can go below that threshold temporarily,
这样我就可以暂时低于这个阈值，
to see whether something's going to get inserted
看看是否会插入一些东西，
to then put me above of that threshold
然后让我超过这个阈值，
to avoid having to do this prematurely.
以避免过早地这样做。
Again, this is why Postgres are going to call their balance,
这就是为什么 Postgres 称他们的平衡，
they call their B+ tree as a non balanceed B+ tree,
他们把他们的 B+ 树称为非平衡 B+ 树，
because they can violate this, this requirement.
因为他们可能会违反这个要求。
Next question is,
下一个问题是，
how do you want to handle variable length keys,
你希望如何处理可变长度键，
I think somebody brought this up.
我想是有人提起了这件事。
So the,
所以，
we could sort of try to approach it like a, like a column store,
我们可以试着像一个列存储一样处理它，
we want everything to be fixed length.
我们希望每个东西都是固定长度的。
So one way to do that is
要做到这个的一种方法是，
actually you don't store the keys themselves in in every node,
实际上你不在每个节点中存储键本身，
you store a pointer to the key, like the record ID,
而是存储一个指向键的指针，比如记录 ID ，
because that's always going to be either 32 bits or 64 bits, right.
因为这将始终是 32 位或 64 位，
And actually this, this will save space, too,
实际上，这也将节省空间，
because you know if my keys are all really big,
因为，如果我的键都很大，
I'm not gonna store them,
我就不会存储它们，
you know can, again, the B B+ tree is a copy of what's in the table,
再次， B+ 树是表格中的副本，
I only have to store to just the pointer to the record ID,
我只需存储到指向记录 ID 的指针，
in the, in the, in the, the nodes.
在节点中。
Is that a good idea or a bad idea?
这是个好主意还是坏主意？
He's right, doesn't sound like a good idea,
他是对的，听起来不是个好主意，
because it causes a lot of non sequential I/O.
因为它会导致很多非顺序的 I/O 。
Think I'm traversing down my my nodes
考虑我正在向下遍历我的节点，
and I gotta figure out whether I go left and right,
我必须弄清楚我是向左还是向右，
I don't have those guideposts in my node,
我的节点上没有那些路标，
I got to go follow the pointer to go get that tuple in that page,
我必须沿着指针去获取页面中的那个 tuple ，
then do the lookup to find what I need.
然后进行查找以找到我需要的东西。
And again, while I'm doing this,
再次，当我这样做的时候，
I'm holding latches in my data structure
我在我的数据结构中持有 latch ，
and that's going to be really slow.
这将是非常缓慢的。
Yeah, so nobody does this in a database system.
是的，所以没人会在数据库系统中这样做。
The variant of this of B+ tree is called T-Trees,
这种 B+ 树的变体称为 T 树，
I figure what the T stands for,
我弄清楚 T 代表什么，
I think it stands for the dude's name,
我想这表示这家伙的名字，
in the diagrams, the nodes look like [Ts],
在图表中，节点看起来像 [T] ，
but I think the email said,
但我想电子邮件说的是，
oh yes, the guy's name, but whatever.
哦，是的，那个人的名字，但是无论什么。
In-memory databases did this in the 80s,
内存数据库在 80 年代做了这个，
because they wanted to save space,
因为他们想要节省空间，
you want to have duplicate keys in your, in your B+ tree,
你想在你的 B+ 树上有重复的键，
because they didn't have a lot of memory.
因为他们没有太多的内存。
But again, nobody does this now in a real system,
但再说一次，现在没有人在真正的系统中这样做，
because it's it's so expensive to do that other lookup,
因为执行其他查找的成本太高了，
it's just it's easier to just copy the key.
只是复制键更容易。
You could support variable length nodes,
你可以支持可变长度节点，
or the size of the node can can vary within the index
或者，节点的大小在索引中可能会有所不同，
and you have to do this,
你必须这样做，
because you don't know the size of the,
因为你不知道大小，
you want to have the same potential number of keys in every single node,
你希望在每个节点中都有相同的潜在数量的键，
but nobody has,
但是没有人，
you know, you may not have enough space to store all those keys within that node.
你可能没有足够的空间在节点中存储所有这些键。
As far as I know, only academic systems do this,
据我所知，只有学术系统才会这样做，
nobody does this in the real world.
在现实世界中，没有人会这样做。
Padding is another approach to handle this,
填充是处理这个问题的另一种方法，
as we talked before in, in, in column stores,
正如我们之前在列存储中讨论的那样，
again, I think this is rare,
再次，我认为这是罕见的，
what most people do is that,
大多数人会做的是，
they would have a essentially a slot array,
他们基本上会有一个 slot array ，
a slotted page approach, like we saw in table, table pages,
像我们在表页中看到的那样的 slot 页方法，
where you have this array of pointers within
你有这个指针数组，
it's also within the page you're looking at or to another overflow page.
它在你查看的页面中或者另一个溢出页面。
And again it's, it's, how do you say this,
再次，怎么说这个，
it's, it's just like the overflow values we saw before,
它就像我们之前看到的溢出值一样，
where you just,
你只是，
you know, you know that the thing I'm looking for is not my page,
你知道我要找的东西不是我的页面，
I got to go somewhere else and go get it.
我得去别的地方去获取它。
Now we got to talk about how we actually want to go find the keys,
现在我们要谈谈到底如何查找键，
once you know, once we land on the node,
一旦我们到了节点上，
we bring it in a memory
我们把它带到内存中，
and we're looking for a key, decide to go left or right,
我们寻找一个键，决定向左还是向右，
or whether we have the match we're looking for in our leaf node,
或者我们是否在叶子节点中找到我们想要的匹配，
we got decide how we're going do that match.
我们必须决定如何进行匹配。
So the easiest approach is to just do a linear scan.
所以最简单的方法就是做一个线性扫描。
Just think of an array,
考虑一个数组，
doesn't matter if it's sort of not,
无论它是否排序，
I just start at the beginning
我只是从头开始，
and I scan along until I find the thing I'm looking for,
一直往看，直到找到我要找的东西，
in this case here, I'm looking for key 8,
在这个情况下，我在找键 8 ，
it's simple, it's dumb, it works, right?
这很简单，这太傻了，这很管用，是吧？
We can do a little better though,
不过，我们可以做得更好一些，
with SIMD,
使用 SIMD ，
actually it,
实际上它是，
who here has taken 418/618?
在座的谁学过 418/618 ？
Nobody, okay,
没有人，好的，
who here doesn't know what SIMD is?
在座的谁不知道 SIMD 是什么？
Okay, Okay, SIMD stands for single instruction multiple data,
好的，好的， SIMD 代表单指令流多数据流，
it's a class of instructions you can have on modern CPU,
这是现代 CPU 上有的一类指令，
that allow you to basically have a vector register,
它允许你有一个向量寄存器，
you put a bunch of values in it
你把一堆值放进去，
and then there's a single instruction to do, like do something on it,
然后有一条指令，在上面做一些事情，
like you can put a bunch of numbers in one vector,
比如你可以把一堆数字放进一个向量，
a bunch of numbers and another vector
一堆数字和另一个向量，
and do add them together and the output goes into another vector,
然后把它们加在一起，输出到另一个向量，
we'll cover this when we talk about query execution,
我们将在讨论查询执行时讨论这个，
but this is a very common technique used in modern systems,
但这是现代系统中使用的一种非常常见的技术，
this is what made snowflake special, 10 years ago.
这就是 10 年前让 Snowflake 变得特别的地方。
All right, so what I can do is,
好的，所以我能做的是，
instead of doing, looking at every single key one after another, try to find 8,
不是一个接一个地查看每个键，试着找到 8 ，
I can instead use a SIMD intrinsic,
我可以使用 SIMD 内部函数，
in this case here,
在这个例中，
this is for x86
这是对于 x86 ，
to do evaluation 32-bit integers on, 128-bit registers.
在 128 位寄存器上对 32 位整数进行求值。
So I store, I'm looking for 8,
所以我查找 8 ，
I store eight copies of 8
我存储八个（应该是四个） 8 的副本，
and my SIMD register has four lanes,
我的 SIMD 寄存器有 4 个通道，
and then now in a single instruction,
现在，在一条指令中，
I can do an evaluation of those eight 8 or four 8 with the keys in my array,
我可以用数组中的键对这八个 8 或四个 8 求值，
and then I'll get a bit mask,
然后我会得到位 mask ，
that says 0 if there's no match,
如果没有匹配，则为 0 ，
1, if there's a match.
如果匹配，则为 1 。
So in this case here,
所以在这种情况下，
now it's a single instruction to do that evaluation,
现在只有一条指令来进行求值，
and I can do that way more efficiently than going one after another.
我可以用这种方式比一个接一个地做更有效率。
In this case,
在这种情况下，
and then for this one, I don't have a match,
对于这个，我没有匹配，
so I got to slide it over,
所以我把它滑过去，
do the look at the next one,
看看下一个，
I have to recognize that, I only have three keys and not four,
我必须认识到我只有三个键，而不是四个，
so I gotta play little tricks to make sure,
所以我必须玩一些小把戏来确保，
like I don't end up with a false positive.
就像我不会得到假的确定。
But in this case here,
但在这种情况下，
now I have 8 equals 8 in that first lane
现在我在第一个通道上有 8 等于 8 ，
and I have a match.
我有一个匹配。
So I can do this more efficiently
所以我可以更有效地这样做，
and then doing this,
然后做这个，
it is still linear,
它仍然是线性的，
but I'm doing it in batches
但我是分批进行的，
and the hardware can support that.
硬件可以支持它。
Next approach to obviously do binary search,
下一个方法，显然是进行二分搜索，
assuming it's sorted, this is easy,
假设它是排序的，这很容易，
you jump in the middle,
你跳到中间，
my value is greater than,
我的值大于，
the key is greater, less than the one I'm looking for,
键大于，小于我要找的那个，
I jump to the next side and so forth
我跳到下一边，以此类推，
until I find my match,
直到我找到我匹配的，
then I'm done.
然后我就完成了。
This is what most systems will do.
这是大多数系统都会做的事情。
It depends on the hardware of,
这取决于硬件，
so in Postgres be 8 kilobytes, right,
所以在 Postgres 中是 8 千字节，
but again, the number of keys you can store in that node
但是同样，你可以在节点中存储的键的数量
is going to depend on the key, what the type of the key is.
取决于键的类型。
All right.
好的。
So, binary search is the most common one.
所以，二分搜索是最常见的一种。
The,
这个，
you could do this,
你可以做这个，
I don't think any,
我不认为任何，
outside academia, nobody does this.
学术界之外，没有人这样做。
You can do interpolation search
你可以做插值搜索，
and this works,
这个方法可行，
if you know there's no gaps in your keys
如果你的键中没有间隔，
and they're always in monotonically increasing order,
并且它们总是按单调递增的顺序排列，
like if you have a primary key,
如果你有一个主键，
that's a like, like auto increment value,
那就像自动增量值，
like plus one, plus one, plus one, plus one,
比如加一，加一，加一，
and again I assume I don't have any gaps,
再次，我假设我没有任何间隔，
then it's just simple math
那么这只是一个简单的数学运算，
to figure out exactly within my array,
在我的数组中准确地计算出，
I know the low point,
我知道最低点，
I know the min value, the max value,
我知道最小值，最大值，
I have know number of keys that I have
我知道键的数量，
and I just do a simple formula like this
我只需要做一个简单的公式，
to jump exactly to the offset that I need
跳到我需要的偏移量，
and I'm done.
我就完成了。
This is the fastest approach,
这是最快的方法，
faster than binary search,
比二分搜索快，
faster than SIMD,
比 SIMD 快，
but again, you have, you can't have gaps to do this.
但是再次，你不能有间隔来做这个。
So, it's rare.
所以，这是很罕见的。
We have, we have 20 minutes left to get through all these optimizations,
我们还有 20 分钟来完成所有这些优化，
let's see how far we can go, okay.
让我们看看我们能走多远，好吧。
Some of these should be pretty obvious,
其中一些应该是非常明显的，
the, the Pointer Swizzling and the Buffered Updates,
Pointer Swizzling 和 Buffered Updates ，
those are probably the most important,
这些可能是最重要的。
Deduplication too.
Deduplication 也是。
All right, so just like in a column store,
好的，所以，就像在列存储中一样，
we should recognize that,
我们应该认识到，
the keys that are going to be in our, in our B+ tree,
将在我们 B+ 树中的键，
they're going to be in the same value domain,
它们将位于相同的值域中，
because they're all coming from the same, same attributes,
因为它们都来自相同的属性，
furthermore, they're sorted,
此外，它们是经过排序的，
which is even better for compression, right.
这对于压缩来说更好。
So there's a bunch of things we can take advantage of
所以，我们可以利用很多东西，
recognizing that the values are going to be very similar,
来认识到这些值将非常相似，
to, to reduce the size of the keys we actually have the store.
以减小我们存储的键的大小。
So in this case here,
在这种情况下，
we can do what's called prefix compression,
我们可以进行前缀压缩，
and we can identify that,
我们可以确定，
we're going to have a bunch of keys that are going to be very close to each other in leographical ordering
我们将拥有一组在物理顺序上彼此非常接近的键，
and they're going to have overlapping portions of of data.
它们将具有重叠的数据部分。
So instead of storing complete copies of the keys,
所以我们不是存储密钥的完整副本，
we store the common prefix, in this case here, rob,
我们存储公共前缀，在这里是 rob ，
and then we store the the remaining suffix that's, that's unique, right.
然后我们存储剩余的后缀，那是唯一的。
That's pretty easy, that's nice.
这很容易，这很好。
Next technique is to do deduplication
下一项技术是重复数据删除，
and the idea here is that,
这里的想法是，
we're going to have a bunch of keys,
我们将拥有一堆键，
that are end up with the same value over and over again
以相同的值结束，
in the, in the, in, in the same nodes
在相同的节点中，
and again ignoring the prefix, or putting the, putting the record ID at the end,
再次，忽略前缀，将记录 ID 放在末尾，
because that one, the system knows that it's doing that,
因为系统知道它做的，
it can pull that piece, piece out,
它可以取出那一块，
but if I have a bunch of non unique keys,
但如果我有一堆非唯一的键，
that are that are going to end up in the same node,
它们最终将在同一个节点中，
it's just like prefix sorting or prefix compression,
这就像前缀排序或前缀压缩，
I just store the the duplicate key once,
我只需存储一次重复的键，
then have a posting list
然后拥有一个[发布]列表，
or a list of all the values that correspond to that key,
或与该键对应的所有值的列表，
and now I'm only storing one copy of that key, right.
现在我只需存储那个键的一个副本。
Postgres added this in, I think in, Postgres 15,
Postgres 添加这个，我想是 Postgres 15 ，
I think it came out last year,
我想它是去年发布的，
and it's a pretty significant drop in size your nodes.
它对你的节点大小有了很大的下降。
Yeah, so his question is,
好的，所以他的问题是，
how, how do we know, How do we know that,
我们怎么知道，
we should interpret what this is,
我们应该解释这是什么，
these are values, not keys,
这些是值，而不是键，
this is just a mockup,
这只是一个模型，
you wouldn't, you wouldn't sort exactly the page like this,
你不会完全像这样对页面进行排序，
you would have obviously, lengths of the number of elements you're storing,
显然，你将拥有存储的元素数量的长度，
just not showing that,
不只是显示的这样，
you have additional metadata,
你有其他元数据，
they know where the offsets are.
它们知道偏移量在哪里。
We can also do suffix truncation
我们还可以进行后缀截断，
and again, because the inner nodes don't have to be the exact copies of the keys,
因为内部节点不必是键的完全副本，
because those keys might not exist in the leaf nodes,
因为那些键可能不存在于叶子节点中，
we maybe don't have to store the entire key,
所以我们可能不必存储整个键，
we just need enough of the of the key key prefix
我们只需要足够的键前缀，
to discriminate whether we need to go left or right.
来区分我们需要向左还是向右。
So in this case here,
所以在这种情况下，
I have keys abc up to k,
我有键 abc 到 k ，
and then lmno up to v,
然后 lmno 到 v ，
the only thing that that really matters in this case here is
在本例中，真正重要的东西是，
say just the first three characters of both of these two strings,
比如这两个字符串的前三个字符，
so my inner nodes only need to store the minimum prefix,
所以我的内部节点只需要存储最小前缀，
that we need to decide whether to go left or right.
我们需要决定是向左还是向右。
And of course, now the challenge is like,
当然，现在的挑战是，
if I insert a key,
如果我插入一个键，
could you know, could be in between them,
可能在它们之间，
maybe I got to go back and get the original keys
也许我得回去，获取原始键，
to decide what the prefix should be,
来决定前缀应该是什么，
but in some environments, this might be the right thing.
但在某些环境中，这可能是正确的。
So, Pointer Swizzling is a common technique,
所以， Pointer Swizzling 是一种常见的技术，
that's going to allow us to minimize the amount of lookup,
它将允许我们最大限度地减少查找量，
we have to do in our buffer pool page table.
我们必须在缓冲池页表中所做的。
Because again, when we are traversing the nodes, or traversing the tree structure,
因为同样，当我们遍历节点，遍历树结构时，
what I keep calling a, pointers,
我一直叫做指针，
they're really page IDs.
它们实际上是页面 ID 。
So I got to go to the page table and say,
所以我要去页面表说，
okay, well, if this page exists,
好的，如果这个页面存在，
give me, give me the, the pointer to it, right.
给我指向它的指针。
So if I want to say find keys greater than 3,
所以，如果我想说查找大于 3 的键，
I started my root node here
我从这里的根节点开始，
and I look at the keys
我查看键，
and decide whether I want to go left and right,
并决定是否要向左和向右移动，
in this case here, I want to go left,
在这种情况下，我想向左，
but then the, the value in this node here is going to be the page number,
但是，这个节点中的值将是页码，
so page #2,
所以页 #2 ，
so now I got to go down my buffer pool
现在我要去我的缓冲池，
and say, okay, give me, give me the pointer to page #2,
然后说，好的，给我指向页 #2 的指针，
likewise on the bottom here,
同样在底部，
I want to scan along the sibling nodes,
我想沿着兄弟节点扫描，
go from page #2 to page #3,
从页 #2 转到页 #3 ，
I got to go back to the buffer pool.
我必须回到缓冲池。
So the technique, the idea of Pointer Swizzling is that,
所以这个技术， Pointer Swizzling 的想法是，
if you pin the page in the buffer pool,
如果你将页固定在缓冲池中，
say this page cannot be cannot be evicted,
比如这个页不能被驱逐，
then any, any page that points to that page you pinned
然后，任何指向你固定的页面的页面，
you have to be pinned too,
你也必须固定，
you replace its contents with the actual pointer in memory,
你将其内容替换为内存中的实际指针，
and so now when I'm, when I'm scanning, when I'm, you know, traversing my tree,
所以现在当我扫描，当我遍历我的树时，
I'm not going to the buffer pool to say,
我不会去缓冲池说，
go do this, look up for me, for this page,
去做这个，帮我查找这个页，
I had the thing exactly what I'm looking for.
我有我寻找的东西。
So, thing like the root node,
所以，像根节点一样，
everyone's always going to that in your B+ tree and say,
每个都会去你的 B+ 树，然后说，
and then they're always going to go down to the the next level,
然后它们总是会下到下一层，
so instead of having to do page page lookups in the buffer pool,
所以，不必在缓冲池中进行页面查找，
would get down the next level,
会进入下一级，
I have the pointer to know where to go directly.
我有知道直接去哪里的指针。
And obviously, you don't want to store this pointer on disk,
显然，你不希望将这个指针存储在磁盘上，
you know, if the page gets flushed,
如果页面被刷新，
because now you load it back in,
因为现在你重新加载它，
you have this pointer that goes to nowhere,
你就会得到这个指针，它不会指向任何地方，
and that would be bad,
这将是糟糕的，
so there's bookkeeping you have to do
所以你必须做记账，
to make sure,
以确保，
okay, you're going to disk undo this swizzle, what got swizzled
好的，你要去磁盘，取消这个交换，
to make sure that nobody points to it,
以确保没有人指向它，
and then also, too,
然后也是，
you don't want, you know, you don't want this page to get evicted,
你不想这个页面被驱逐，
this thing have a swizzle pointer
这个东西有一个交换指针，
and now it's pointing to some other page,
现在它指向一些其他页面，
that got swapped in that frame
交换到 frame 中，
and does it, and, and it's not part of the B+ tree
它不是 B+ 树的一部分，
and then you would have a seg fault,
然后你会有一个段错误，
because it starts interpreting bytes that that it should,
因为它开始解释字节，
starts interpreting bytes in a way that it should.
开始以它应该解释的方式来解释字节。
So the reason why I talk about this for the B+ tree
所以我之所以为 B+ 树讨论这个，
and not for the hash table stuff
而不是哈希表的东西，
or not for the regular heap stuff,
或者不是常规的堆的东西，
is because we already have this hierarchy in our tree structure here,
是因为我们在这里的树结构中已经有了这个层次结构，
we would know that if we swizzle anything below us,
我们会知道，如果我们交换我们下面的任何东西，
we want to make sure that this thing doesn't get unpinned,
我们想要确保这个东西不会被取消固定，
that this thing doesn't get unpinned,
这个东西不会被取消固定，
before its children get unpinned,
在它的子节点被取消固定之前，
and that way, the pointers are always valid.
这样，指针总是有效的。
Right, this thing again,
好的，又是这个东西，
when you you're building project #1,
当你在做项目 #1 时，
this thing, all the work you have to go, do to go, go look on the page,
这个东西，你要做的所有工作都要，去查看页面，
you will go find the thing you're looking for,
你会找到你要找的东西，
the frame, not there,
frame ，不在那里，
and then go evict something, right,
然后去驱逐一些东西，
you skip all of that,
你可以跳过所有这些，
you update the LRU-K stuff, right,
你更新 LRU-K 的东西，
by just going directly through the pointers.
只需直接转到指针。
But of course, you lose the metadata of the access patterns
当然，你会丢失访问模式的元数据，
for how these pages are being used,
有关如何使用这些页面，
but again, if it's important enough to pin it and swizzle it,
但同样，如果它足够重要，可以将其固定和交换，
then you probably should stay in memory.
那么你可能应该留在内存中。
All right, to do inserts quickly,
好的，为了快速插入，
the, the most common trick is to pre sort everything,
最常见的技巧是对所有内容进行预排序，
which we'll cover in next week,
我们将在下周讨论这个，
you sort out your keys
你对键进行排序，
and just lay them out as leaf nodes, right,
并将它们作为叶子节点放置，
with your sibling pointers,
使用兄弟指针，
and then build the data structure from the bottom to the top, right.
然后自下而上构建数据结构。
And this is different,
这是不同的，
if I just insert the keys one after another,
如果我一个接一个地插入键，
I would start from the top and go down
我就会从上面开始，然后向下，
and start have to do all the splits and so forth,
必须做所有的拆分，等等，
I skip all of that, that I just pre sort things,
我跳过所有这些，只是预先排序，
build the scaffolding on top of it,
在上面搭建脚手架，
and this technique is very common as well.
这种技术也很常见。
All right, so the last optimization I want to talk about is,
好的，我想讨论的最后一个优化是，
you know, we make a big deal about how,
我们很看重怎么做，
the nice thing about the B+ tree is that,
B+ 树的好处在于，
it's balanced, everything's always log(n)
它是平衡的，所有东西都是 log(n) ，
and our lookups can be really fast,
我们的查找可以非常快，
because again, everything is log(n) to get the leaf node
因为，所有东西都是 log(n) 获得叶子节点，
and then we can try to get as much sequential access as, sequential I/O as we can.
然后我们可以尝试获得尽可能多的顺序访问，顺序 I/O 。
But, of course, the challenge is that,
但是，当然，挑战是，
updates are going to be expensive for us,
更新对我们来说将是昂贵的，
because we have to maintain this balance, this balance property,
因为我们必须保持这种平衡属性，
anytime a thread comes along and inserts or deletes,
当线程出现并插入或删除时，
they may draw the short straw
它们可能会抽中短签，
and be responsible for reorganizing the entire data structure.
负责重新组织整个数据结构。
And so, ideally, what we want is
所以，理想情况下，我们需要的是，
a way to delay the updates to the data structure.
一种延迟数据结构更新的方法。
In such a way,
以这样一种方式，
that we can accumulate them
我们可以累积它们，
and then at some later point
然后在以后的某个点上，
we have enough,
我们有足够的，
we say, okay,
我们说，好的，
let me go ahead and apply all my changes in a batch,
让我继续并批量应用我的所有修改，
and then, yes, I may have to reorganize things,
然后，是的，我可能不得不重新组织东西，
but I'm doing it all once,
但我所有只做一次，
I can amortize the cost, of, of making those changes
我可以摊销做这些修改的花费，
and now your writes could potentially be faster,
现在你的写入可能会更快，
because you don't, you don't, you don't have to worry about,
因为你不必担心，
I'm gonna have to split every time I insert something new.
每次我插入新的东西，我都得拆分。
So, there's a line of work on
所以，有一系列的工作，
what is called write optimize B trees or B+ trees,
称为写入优化 B 树或 B+ 树，
these have sometimes are also called Bε trees,
这些有时也被称为 Bε 树，
you'll see it with a little, little ε symbol,
你会看到它有一个小写 ε 符号，
there's a commercial variant from the Tokutek guys called fractal trees,
Tokutek 的人有一种商业变体叫分形树，
but it's basically branding,
但它基本上是品牌，
it's, it's the same idea.
它的想法是一样的。
And the idea is basically,
这个想法基本上是，
now at every single root node and inner node,
现在在每个根节点和内部节点，
I'm going to have a mod log,
我将有一个 mod 日志，
just like MySQL had for their pages,
就像 MySQL 在他们的页面所做的，
when they were doing compression,
在他们做压缩时，
and anytime a new update comes along,
无论何时出现新的更新，
instead of propagating those changes all the way down to the leaf nodes,
不是将这些修改一直传播到叶子节点，
I'm going to violate the property we talked about in the B+ tree,
我会违反我们在 B+ 树中讨论过的属性，
where the leaf nodes have to be, where the actual values are,
叶子节点必须是实际值所在的，
and I can, I can insert my entries into the mod log.
我可以将我的条目插入到 mod 日志中。
So if I want to insert 7,
所以，如果我想插入 7 ，
again, instead of having traverse down
再次，不是向下遍历，
and figure out where 7 should go,
并计算出 7 应该放在哪里，
I just put it in the root,
我只是将它放在根中，
same thing, I want to delete 10,
同样的事情，我想删除 10 ，
Instead of putting it into the,
不是把它放入，
going down and deleting it and then potentially doing a merge,
向下，删除它，然后可能进行合并，
I'll just put it in the mod log.
我只会把它放到 mod 日志中。
All right?
好的？
So now if a query comes up and wants to find 10,
所以，现在如果出现一个查询，并希望找到 10 ，
well, as I traverse down,
好的，当我向下遍历时，
I look in the mod log and say,
我查看 mod 日志，并说，
okay, is the thing I'm looking for here.
好的，我要找的东西在这里。
So in this case here,
所以在这个例子中，
I I I deleted 10,
我删除 10 ，
it's in my mod log,
它在我的 mod 日志中，
so when I do my lookup,
所以当我查找的时候，
I would find the entry here and I'm done,
我会在这里找到条目，然后就完成了，
I don't need to go to the bottom,
我不需要去底部，
and to actually see the change.
真正看到变化。
Of course, what's the obvious problem with this?
当然，这有什么明显的问题？
The buffers get full, right.
缓冲区会满，是吧。
So when that happens,
所以当这种情况发生时，
then you got to cascade down the, the changes,
你必须级联修改，
but the idea is here,
但这里的想法是，
you're doing this incrementally and in batches,
你增量地、批量地做这些，
and you basically, you don't have to apply any modifications
你不必应用任何修改，
until you get to the structure of the data structure
直到你到达数据结构，
until you get to the, to, to the leaf nodes.
直到你到达叶子节点。
So if I insert 40,
所以如果我插入 40 ，
I just move my previous changes,
我只需要移动之前的修改，
insert 7, and insert 10 here
插入 7 ，在这里插入 10 ，
and I leave, and you put insert 40 there.
然后把插入 40 放在这里。
And at some point,
在某个时候，
if I keep going this thing,
如果我继续这样做，
this thing cascades down
这个东西级联下来，
and this thing is full,
这个东西是满的，
then I go ahead and apply my changes.
然后我继续，应用我的修改。
Yes.
是的。
Yeah, so the question is,
是的，所以问题是，
could this potentially make reads go really slow,
这是否可能会导致读取很慢，
because, as I'm scanning along here,
因为，当我在这里扫描时，
I have to do sequential scans within the mod log
我必须在 mod 日志中进行顺序扫描，
to find to see why the thing I'm looking for is in there.
以找到为什么我要找的东西在那里。
Yes, but then like these, these different implementations of Bε trees,
是的，但是就像，这些不同的 Bε 树的实现，
they have bloom filters in front of these things
它们在这些东西前面有布隆过滤器，
to say is the key I'm looking for,
说是否是我寻找的键，
actually, even in my mod log,
甚至在我的 mod 日志中，
if yes, then go look for it,
如果是，那就去查找它，
and bloom filters are cheap to maintain,
布隆过滤器很容易维护，
and they're not very big.
而且它们也不是很大。
So this is an old idea, that old, 2003 old,
所以这是一个老的想法， 2003 年，
B+ tree's, 1972,
B+ 树是 1972 年，
so maybe that's not that old,
所以可能没有那么老，
is an old idea,
但是一个老的想法，
what does this look also look like,
这个看起来像什么，
what we talked about before,
我们之前讨论过的，
log structure storage, right,
日志结构存储，
same idea, that we can append these log, log entries
同样的想法，我们可以附加这些日志条目，
and then batch them up
然后批量处理它们，
and apply them at some later point.
并在稍后的某个时候应用它们。
So I said, you guys, we've seen this idea over and over again.
所以我说，我们已经一遍又一遍地看到了这个想法。
So Tokutek, they rebranded their implementation of Bε tree as fractal trees,
所以 Tokutek ，他们将他们的 Bε 树的实现重新命名为分形树，
and then they had a storage engine for MySQL, that,
然后他们有了一个用于 MySQL 的存储引擎，
I got think up, got bought by Percona
我想想，被 Percona 收购，
and I think I got deprecated last year,
我想我去年被废弃了，
so, they had probably the most robust implementation from a few years ago,
所以，它们可能是几年前最健壮的实现，
that's dead,
那已经死了，
SplinterDB is a key value store, embedded key value store from VMware,
SplinterDB 是一个 VMware 编写的嵌入式键值存储，
written, actually, somebody here that was,
实际上是由这里的人编写的，
he was a researcher at VMware,
他是 VMware 的一名研究人员，
but he was getting his MBA here at Tepper at CMU
但他是在 CMU 的 Tepper 获得 MBA 的，
and another guy working on this,
另一个致力于此的人，
he's now professor at Cornell,
他现在是康奈尔大学的教授，
but this is basically a sort of a super optimized version of this.
但这基本上是一种超级优化的版本。
And the RelationalAI is a relational knowledge based,
RelationAI 是一个基于关系型知识的，
graph [] on top, knowledge graph [] on top of relational database system,
关系型数据库之上的知识图谱[]，
that implements Bε trees do fast updates.
实现了 Bε 树，进行快速更新。
So this is not that common,
所以这并不常见，
but you know, this is something,
但是，这是，
I I suspect we'll see more and more of in the future,
我怀疑我们在未来会看到越来越多，
I mean, RocksDB doesn't need this,
我的意思是， RocksDB 不需要这个，
because RocksDB already is a log structure merge tree,
因为 RocksDB 已经是一个日志结构合并树，
and you're essentially getting the same idea, the same properties.
你基本上得到了相同的概念、相同的属性。
All right, so we have six minutes left.
好的，所以我们还剩六分钟。
So let's pop up in Postgres,
所以，让我们打开 Postgres ，
and do a quick demo.
做一个快速的 demo 。
So here I going to demonstrate the difference between,
所以，在这里我将演示两者的区别，
I turn the lights off,
我关掉灯，
demonstrate the difference between MySQL,
演示 MySQL 的区别，
oh, sorry, not MySQL.
抱歉，不是 MySQL 。
Nope, sorry,
不，抱歉，
works.
可以了。
There we go, I had the light the first time.
好了，我第一次关这个灯。
So I want to demonstrate
所以，我想演示，
the difference between a hash index and a B+ tree on, on data
哈希索引和 B+ 树在数据上的区别，
and we can see what the database system is going to choose to use to run queries.
我们可以看到数据库系统将选择使用什么来运行查询。
So the data set I'm going to use is going to be,
所以我要使用的数据集是，
I think it 21 million email addresses from a few years ago, right,
我想是，几年前的 2100 万个电子邮件地址，
because it's all on,
因为所有都在，
it's, yeah, so 27 27 million email addresses, right.
是的， 2700 万个电子邮件地址。
And so, I'm not going to run this in real time,
所以，我不打算实时运行它，
but basically I've created two indexes,
但我已经创建了两个索引，
I created one here on a B+ tree on the emails,
我在电子邮件使用 B+ 创建了一个，
sorry,
抱歉，
and the way it works is like,
它的工作方式类似于，
in Postgres, you say CREATE INDEX, with the name of the index on this table
在 Postgres 中，你说 CREATE INDEX ，加上这个表上的索引名，
and then USING, and you can specify what data structure you want,
然后 USING ，你可以指定所需的数据结构，
so by default, if you don't have the USING clause in Postgres,
所以默认情况下，如果你在 Postgres 中没有 USING 子句，
you, you, you get a B+ tree,
你会得到一个 B+ 树，
but here I'm explicitly telling,
但这里我明确地告诉你，
I want a B+ tree
我想要一个 B+ 树，
and the index already exists,
索引已经存在了，
I don't need to do that.
我不需要这么做。
And then I have the build the same thing on on the same column,
然后，我使用在相同的列上构建相同的内容，
I'll build it on on, using a hash table,
使用哈希表构建，
and I just say USING HASH,
我只是说 USING HASH ，
and again, I already have that.
再次，我已经有了。
So let me turn off a bunch of other optimizations in postgres,
所以，让我关闭 Postgres 中一系列其他优化，
that we don't need to worry about just yet,
我们不需要担心，
so I can do queries like this, right,
所以我可以像这样进行查询，
SELECT MIN(email) FROM emails,
SELECT MIN(email) FROM emails ，
and I get some random thing like this,
我会得到一些随机的东西，
but again, if I put the EXPLAIN keyword in front of it,
但同样，如果我把 EXPLAIN 关键字放在它前面，
Postgres will tell me what the query plan is, right,
Postgres 会告诉我查询计划是什么。
so here it's going to tell me,
这里它将告诉我，
I going to do an index only scan using the B+ tree
我将使用 B+ 树进行仅索引扫描，
and it tells me what the conditional, conditional is,
它会告诉我条件是什么，
So we didn't talk about index only scan,
我们没有讨论仅索引扫描，
sometimes cover scans or covering indexes,
有时是覆盖扫描或覆盖索引，
basically, Postgres recognizes that,
基本上， Postgres 认识到，
all the data or all the columns I need to answer this query can be found in the index,
回答这个查询所需的所有数据或列都可以在索引中找到，
so even though they're storing the record IDs in the leaf nodes,
所以，即使它们将记录 ID 存储在叶子节点中，
I don't need to actually follow those record ID
我不需要跟踪这些记录 ID
to get the data for the actual tuple,
来获得实际 tuple 的数据，
all everything I need for this query can be answered from the index, right,
这个查询所需的所有内容都可以从索引中得到回答。
because again going back to my query,
因为，再次回到我的查询，
it was just select the min email from, from the email address
它只是从电子邮件地址中选择了最小的 email ，
and the index is on email,
索引在 email 上，
so once I go all the way to the right side of the tree or left side of the tree,
所以，一旦我一直走到树的右侧或树的左侧，
that has all the data I'm looking for.
就有了我要寻找的所有数据。
So that's why it told me it can do an index only scan,
这就是为什么它告诉我它可以进行仅索引扫描，
so that's fine.
所以这很好。
So let's see,
让我们来看看，
now, if we want to do something like this,
现在，如果我们想做这样的事情，
we want to say,
我们想说，
give me, give me all the emails where the first letter is a,
给我所有第一个字母是 a 的 email ，
but I'm do a LIMIT 1
但我做了一个 LIMIT 1 ，
and you get somebody like this.
你得到像这样的。
And I can do EXPLAIN
我可以做 EXPLAIN ，
and see what it actually tells me what to do,
看看它告诉了我做了什么，
so in this case here,
所以在这种情况下，
Postgres says,
Postgres 说，
even though I have, I have that B+ tree index, that is sorted on emails,
即使我有 B+ 树索引，它在 emails 上进行排序，
Postgres says, it wants to do a sequential scan,
Postgres 说，它想要进行顺序扫描，
because it recognized that the thing I'm looking for,
因为它注意到我寻找的东西，
you know, I'm looking for all, all emails that start with a,
我寻找所有以 a 开头的电子邮件，
that's at some middle point in the tree,
位于树的某个中间点，
and since it's unbounded,
由于它是无界的，
I'm not specifying like,
我没有指定，
at least in the scan size,
至少在扫描大小上，
I'm not specifying the end marker,
我没有指定结束标记，
it would say, okay, you got to scan to the entire end,
它会说，好的，你必须扫描到整个[末端]，
now, it's not smart enough
现在，它还不够聪明，
to recognize I have a limit 1 there, right,
意识到我有一个 LIMIT 1 ，
so what it really should have done is
所以，它真正应该做的是，
just probe down the index, find the first thing, and then popped out and done,
深入索引，找到第一个，然后弹出，完成，
but in this case here,
但在这件事上，
Postgres wasn't smart enough to figure that out, right.
Postgres 还不够聪明来解决这个。
And it can't pick the hash index,
它不能选择哈希索引，
because again, I'm doing a wild card search,
因为我执行通配符搜索，
I don't have the actual full key, right.
我没有实际的完整键。
So you can see this in other ways,
所以你可以从其他方面来看这个，
so in this case here,
所以在这个例子中，
I want to find all emails where it's greater than Andy,
我想找出所有比 andy 大的电子邮件，
again, I doing sequencial scan,
再次，做顺序扫描，
but now if I do something like this,
但现在如果我做这样的事情，
find all emails where,
找出所有电子邮件，
find all emails where the the first letter, the string starts with zzzz,
找出所有以 zzzz 开头的电子邮件字符串，
now I'm on the right side of the tree,
现在我在树的右侧，
and Postgres recognizes, based on the distribution,
Postgres 注意到，根据分布情况，
okay, well, you're far enough along the tree,
好的，你在树上走得够远了，
where I'm going to scan along,
我要扫描，
so it's okay for me to do the index scan,
所以我可以进行索引扫描，
because that's still, that's going to be less data than doing complete sequencial scan, right.
因为这仍然会比完全顺序扫描的数据量要少。
And at no point, did postgres decide to use the hash index,
没有任何时候， Postgres 没有决定使用哈希索引，
because again, I'm doing like less than greater than a wildcard matches.
因为再次，我做的是小于等于通配符的匹配。
So we can do something like this,
所以我们可以做这样的事情，
where, now we can say,
现在我们可以说，
you know, find emails where there's exact equality matches using the IN clause,
使用 IN 子句查找完全相等匹配的电子邮件，
and now you see Postgres says,
现在，你可以看到 Postgres 说，
that use the hash index here, right.
在这里使用哈希索引，
the bitmap index scan,
位图索引扫描，
I'll explain that,
我会解释，
it's not what you, not a real bitmap index,
这不是真正的位图索引，
you can see it better,
你可以更好地查看它，
instead of using IN,
不是使用 IN ，
you can use a bunch of ORs, right,
你可以使用很多 OR ，
and now what you see is that,
现在你看到的是，
Postgres has multiple entries for the index scan,
Postgres 有多个索引扫描条目，
where for each of, each of the email addresses,
其中每个电子邮件地址，
I had in that in my WHERE clause,
我在 WHERE 子句中的，
like, you know, something equals something OR something equals something,
比如，某个东西等于某个东西 OR 某个东西等于某个东西，
each of those are going to be separate probe into the hash index,
每个都将分别探测到哈希索引，
and then they maintain a bitmap of the,
然后他们维护一个位图，
I think it's the actual tuple IDs, the tuple offsets,
我认为这是实际的 tuple ID ， tuple 偏移量，
not the, not the page's,
不是页面的，
they maintain a bitmap of the matching values for each of those index probes,
它们为每个索引探测维护匹配值的位图，
and then they OR them up together,
然后他们把它们或在一起，
and then that produces the exact tuples they actually, you actually, you actually would need.
然后产生你需要的两个确切的 tuple 。
And this is sort of similar to what I was saying before,
这和我之前说的有点类似，
you, you figure out what the pages you need from the, from the, from the index first,
你首先从索引中找出你需要的页面，
then go actually go get them,
然后去真正去获取它们，
so they're doing that here,
所以他们在这里这样做，
they're doing much of probes in the index,
他们在索引中执行许多探测，
don't actually get the real data from the tables,
没有实际上从表中获得真正的数据，
doing the OR on the bitmaps,
在位图上做 OR ，
then you have the list of the indexes, list of the records you actually need to go get, right.
然后，你就有了需要获取的记录列表。
Okay, so the next thing I want to do is talk about clustering tables.
好的，接下来我想讨论一下聚集表。
So Postgres doesn't act,
所以， Postgres 没有，
Postgres supports the cluster command,
Postgres 支持聚集命令，
but it doesn't actually,
但它实际上并不，
and it will sort your table,
它将对你的表进行排序，
but it doesn't actually maintain the sorting,
但实际上并不维护排序，
because it, because it's not gonna be organized,
因为它不会被组织起来，
it's not in index organized,
它不在索引组织中，
so you with the cluster command,
所以，你使用聚集命令，
Postgres will sort your data,
Postgres 将对数据进行排序，
but as you start modifying the table,
但是当你开始修改表时，
it can get out of sort of order.
它的排序可能会打乱。
So I'm not going to do this live,
所以我不会现场演示，
because it would take too long,
因为这会花太长时间，
and I realized we're a little over time,
我意识到我们有点超时了，
but the command would be,
但命令是，
basically like this, right,
基本上是这样的，
you would say, CLUSTER the table we want to cluster
你会说， CLUSTER 我们需要聚集的表，
and then let the index you have be clustered on,
然后让索引聚集在一起，
this takes about a minute to run,
这大约需要一分钟运行，
so I've already run it before we class,
所以在我们上课之前我已经运行过了，
so I'm not going to do that,
所以我不会这么做，
but we can go look at,
但是我们可以去看看，
like what's in the first, the first, the first page,
比如第一个页面里面有什么，
again the ctid is the record ID, the offset in Postgres,
再次， ctid 是记录 ID ， Postgres 中的偏移量，
so you do that,
所以你这样做，
that actually that's the unsorteded one,
实际上这是未排序的，
so that looks all random,
所以它看起来都是随机的，
but if I change the name of the table to clustered,
但如果我将表名改为 clustered ，
because of that, sorry,
因为这个，抱歉，
right, now you see that,
好的，现在你可以看到，
in the first page or the first offsets,
在第一个页面或第一个偏移量，
the tuples are actually sorted in that order, right,
tuple 按那个顺序排序，
based on, based on the index,
基于索引，
so if I go ahead and delete one of these entries,
所以，如果我继续，删除其中一个条目，
delete the very first person in their fake email address
删除他们虚假电子邮件地址中的第一个人，
and I go back and do the same scan on the table, right,
我返回，并在表上做同样的扫描，
Postgres didn't fill in that first slot right,
Postgres 没有填充第一个 slot ，
it's empty,
它是空的，
but now if I insert this fake person back in,
但现在如果我把这个假人放回去，
and do the same scan, right,
做同样的扫描，
they're still not in that first page, right.
它们仍然不在第一页上。
So to go find them,
所以，为了找到它们，
we do SELECT *, SELECT ctid FROM emails_clustered,
我们做 SELECT *, SELECT ctid FROM emails_clustered ，
WHERE email = this, right,
WHERE email = 这个，
now they're on page 299,
现在它们在页面 299 上，
I don't know where that is, some random thing,
我不知道它在哪里，一些随机的东西，
but again, it's not in sorted order,
但同样，它不是按排序顺序的，
because, again, Postgres can't maintain the order,
因为 Postgres 不能维护顺序，
because it doesn't have true clustered indexes.
因为它没有真正的聚集索引。
Okay.
好的。
So, B+ trees are important,
所以， B+ 树很重要。
it probably the best choice for your database system,
它可能是你的数据库系统的最佳选择，
Tries are pretty good,
Trie 是相当不错的，
you can have B+ trees or Tries, as I said before,
就像我之前说的，你可以有 B+ 树或 Trie ，
but B+ tree is,
但是 B+ 树是，
there's a bunch of ways of about faster.
有很多更快的方法。
So next class,
所以下一节课，
we talk about how do you actually make your B+ tree thread safe
我们讨论如何让你的 B+ 树线程安全，
by traversing down
通过向下遍历，
and even when you're doing splits and merges,
甚至当你做分裂和合并的时候，
okay, hit it.
好的，开始。